<Document>
  #RMC-14 Rules

  If you are unable to click any of the links, use the in-game guidebook version.

  ##Recent Changes
  Read the relevant sections for the entire text.
  - (Marine roleplay, metagaming) Surrounding a comms tower entirely with reinforced walls to prevent Xenos attacking it without T3s is not allowed.
  - (Survivor roleplay) Survivors should not be rushing to attack the hive before the roundstart xenos have had a chance to evolve (5 minutes).
  - [bold]Hunting or Securing Monkeys to deny Xenonid captures is considered Powergaming.[/bold]
  - (End-of-round grief, Zero tolerance) Suicides done at round-end without a valid roleplay reason are now prohibited and are counted as regular end-of-round grief, and will result in an immediate unappealable 3-hour ban.
  - (General Roleplay Standards) Suicides can be done with a valid roleplay reason. Read the section for more details. An example is suiciding as a survivor in a last stand scenario, when it is clear that you will be captured by xenonids and there is no hope of fighting back.

  ##Admin Decisions Are Final.
  - Rules are enforced as intended. Every example of a rule break cannot be written, thus enforcement is subject to admin interpretation of the rule’s intention.
  - Admins may handle rule breaks through in-character consequences at their discretion. This does not apply to zero tolerance rules.
  - You may file a staff complaint with head staff if you find the decision to be incorrect.

  ##General Information
  Disconnecting from or ignoring/evading admin-helps will result in an appeal only ban.
  This is to prevent bad actors from avoiding issues. If you need to leave urgently, let us know and it will be considered in your appeal.


  All of the below rules apply at all times, including between rounds.

  These rules are neither exactly SS14 or CM13 and should be read in their entirety.

  [textlink="[Ban Definitions]" link="CMBanTypes"]

  [textlink="[Ban Durations]" link="CMBanDurations"]

  ## Zero Tolerance Rules
  You are liable to be banned without warning for breaking these rules.
  - [textlink="Click here to read the zero tolerance rules." link="CMZeroTolerance"]

  ## Core Rules
  These are the general rules of RMC14. Click them for more information.
  - [textlink="1. These are English servers, please only use english." link="CMLanguage"]
  - [textlink="2. Do not use multiple accounts, or alt accounts, and do not share accounts." link="CMMultikey"]
  - [textlink="3. Follow the rules of escalation against non-hostiles." link="CMRulesEscalation"]
  - [textlink="4. Don't use information gained from outside your character's knowledge." link="CMMetaknowledge"]
  - [textlink="5. Don't antagonize your team." link="CMKindness"]
  - [textlink="6. Don't harass or target players across rounds." link="CMMetagrudging"]
  - [textlink="7. Don't immediately quit your role if you do not get the role you want." link="CMRoleRolling"]
  - [textlink="8. Don't quit a head role without notice." link="CMCommandRoles"]

  ## Riots, Mutiny
  - [textlink="1. Mutinies, riots and similar activity require admin permission." link="CMMutinies"]

  ## Military and Command
  These rules also apply to any individual who is promoted or is acting in the place of a MP/Command role (unless they are a member of a hostile force).
  - [textlink="1. Marine Law." link="CMMarineLaw"]
  - [textlink="2. Command and MP are held to a higher standard of play." link="CMHigherStandards"]
  - [textlink="3. MP should try to remain non-lethal and effect arrests, except in specific special circumstances." link="CMLethalForce"]
  - [textlink="4. MP will be expected to answer for use of lethal force." link="CMLethalForceConsequences"]
  - [textlink="5. MP are expected to protect detainees in their custody to the best of their ability." link="CMProtectDetainees"]
  - Only a whitelisted CO or high command (admins) may approve executions.
  - Only a whitelisted CO or high command may pardon a sentence.

  ## Roleplay Rules

  - [textlink="1. General Roleplay Standards." link="CMGeneralRoleplayStandards"]
  - [textlink="2. Marines." link="CMMarineRoleplayStandards"]
  - [textlink="3. Deployment of Marines." link="CMMarineDeployment"]
  - [textlink="4. Command." link="CMCommandRoleplay"]
  - [textlink="5. Xenonids." link="CMXenoRoleplay"]
  - [textlink="6. Survivors." link="CMSurvivorRoleplay"]
  - [textlink="7. Hostile Factions." link="CMHostileFactionRoleplay"]
  - [textlink="8. Chain of Command." link="CMCommandChain"]
</Document>
