<Document>
  ## Mutinies and riots require admin permission.

  [bold]A mutiny is only valid when you are assigned the mutineer role. This will give the character a unique skull-helmet icon visible to everyone, and a message in the chat. Anyone without this icon may not participate as a mutineer.[/bold]

  [bold]General[/bold]

  - All players, including hostile forces, must obtain admin permission before engaging in riots, mutinies or similar activity.
  - Strikes, revolutions, riots, cults, prison riots (excluding hostile forces), and any other type of similar behavior are strictly forbidden without permission.
  - Staff reserve the right to grant or deny these, and to decide if the reason given is sufficient.

  [bold]Mutinies[/bold]

  - Mutiny cannot occur during hijack, and any ongoing mutiny must be ended upon hijack.
  - Only the Acting Commander can be mutinied against. They must be given a chance to stand down peacefully.
  - During the mutiny, attacking any uninvolved, medical, or surrendered personnel is forbidden, as is perma-killing anyone involved.
  - If you have surrendered during a mutiny, you must remain as such.
  - You may not change sides unless you are surrendering.
  - When failed, all sides must be given medical treatment. Commanding Officers or higher are able to deny treatment or battlefield execute mutineers.
  - When succeeded, all sides must be given medical treatment. The next in the command chain should be put in charge.
  - Mutinies must have 3 members minimum.

  [bold]Examples of mutiny reasons:[/bold]
  - Commander incompetence, where the next in line would lead better.
  - Commander takes no actions in leading.
  - Commander refuses to allow evacuation.

  [bold]Examples of invalid mutiny reasons:[/bold]
  - Not liking the commander.
  - Wanting to kill the commander.
  - Trying to take revenge against the commander or CIC.

  [bold]Evacuation Mutinies[/bold]

  - These can be done at any point a shipside evacuation (like during hijack) is allowed, but the Commander is refusing evacuation requests.
  - They may be done by any number of people without permission, with the intent to evacuate from the ship and save their own lives and the lives of others that wish to evacuate.
  - The Commander must still be given a chance to allow the evacuation through negotiation.
  - The most minimal amount of force should be used to start the evacuation.
  - Any roles may join and aid this mutiny, even those normally prevented.

</Document>
