<Document>
  # RMC-14 Rules

  [color=#ff0000][bold]If you are unable to click any links, use the in-game guidebook version, in the escape menu.[/bold][/color]

  [italic]RMC is a roleplaying game with team deathmatch elements. This means players are expected, to an extent, to pretend their character is part of this world in their actions and words. This is the intended experience, and the experience the players of RMC enjoy, and is not always about winning.[/italic]

  ## Recent Changes

  Read the relevant sections for the entire text.

  - [textlink="(CO Provisions, Execution)" link="RMCMarineLawCOProvisions"] Commanding Officers are required to announce their executions.

  - (General Change) Officer Ordered Arrests and all their related mentions and provisions have been removed - excluding those given to Commanding Officers.
  - [textlink="(Marine Law)" link="RMCMarineLaw"] Added text explaining the goals of the MP and an example of problem-solving.
  - [textlink="(Law, Definitions)" link="RMCMarineLawDefinitions"] Added a definition of High Ranking Officers and a link to their provisions.
  - [textlink="(Law, Definitions)" link="RMCMarineLawDefinitions"] Standard Issue Equipment definition added, equipment SOP made more clear.
  - [textlink="(Law, Arresting)" link="RMCMarineLawArresting"] More leeway is granted for accidental bodily harm while deployed.
  - [textlink="(Law, Arresting)" link="RMCMarineLawArresting"] Field Arrests have been reworked. This includes a loosening of movement restrictions of groundside MPs, when given approval.
  - [textlink="(Law, Arresting)" link="RMCMarineLaw"] MP may warn people for minor crimes.
  - [textlink="(Law, Arresting)" link="RMCMarineLawArresting"] Added Investigative detainment, and time restrictions for processing and completing arrests.
  - [textlink="(Law, Charging)" link="RMCMarineLawCharging"] This page has been reorganized for ease of review - following issues of not following procedure.
  - [textlink="Prisoner Rights, Clothing" link="RMCMarineLawAppeals"] Added prisoner rights to have clothing.
  - [textlink="(Law, Synthetics)" link="RMCMarineLawSynthetics"] Synthetics not part of either the UNMC or WeYA now have rights.
  - [textlink="(Law, Variable Crimes)" link="RMCMarineLawCrimesVariable"] Insubordination cannot be applied to orders that are made with the intent to arrest - this should be resisting arrest.
  - [textlink="(Law, Variable Crimes)" link="RMCMarineLawCrimesVariable"] Optional crimes have been merged into variable crimes.
  - [textlink="(Law, Variable Crimes)" link="RMCMarineLawCrimesVariable"] Public Mischief has been added as a variable crime. It relates to false statement that accuses someone of having committed an offence, and similar behavior of wasting time.
  - [textlink="(Law, Variable Crimes)" link="RMCMarineLawCrimesVariable"] Cleaned up the text of the Resisting Arrest crime.
  - [textlink="(Law, Variable Crimes)" link="RMCMarineLawCrimesVariable"] Insubordination now only applies to following orders.
  - [textlink="(Law, Minor Crimes)" link="RMCMarineLawCrimesMinor"] Remade DASO into Disrespecting a Superior, which is an NJP charge that applies to any higher ranking person.
  - [textlink="(SOP, Equipment)" link="RMCMarineSOPEquipment"] Added regulations for the command tablet.


  - [textlink="(Character Names)" link="RMCCharacterNames"] Added guidelines for Skrell and Feroxi.
  - [textlink="(Rules, Core 5)" link="RMCKindness"] Added a notice that if behavior in the Military Police role does not meet community standards, rolebans may be applied less leniently. This may not be an indication of a bad player, but it is an indication that a player doesn't have the understanding required to play MP.
  - [textlink="(Rules, Command)" link="RMCRulesCommand"] Command rules have been condensed into a single page.
  - [textlink="(Rules, Command)" link="RMCRulesCommand"] MP to the best of their ability should be investigating reports of crimes.
  - (Marine Roleplay Standards) Do not use setpose for anything but setting an examinable character pose - such as leaning on a wall.

  ## Admin Decisions Are Final.
  - Rules are enforced as intended. Every example of a rule break cannot be written, thus enforcement is subject to admin interpretation of the rule's intention.
  - Admins may handle rule breaks through in-character consequences at their discretion. This does not apply to zero tolerance rules, and rule breaks may not be requested to be handled this way.
  - Do not argue with the staff. You may file an appeal if you feel the decision to be incorrect, not ignore it.

  ## Important notes

  ### VPNs

  Heavily avoid using a VPN or any similar program to connect or while connected to RMC. You are putting your account at risk, which may result in your account being permanently banned.
  If you have a legitimate reason to use a VPN, you must attempt at least once to connect to the server without a VPN before requesting an exemption for it.

  ## General Information
  Disconnecting from or ignoring/evading admin-helps will result in action being taken.
  This is to prevent bad actors from avoiding issues. If you need to leave urgently, let us know and it will be considered in your appeal.

  - [bold]These rules are not the same as other servers, should be read in their entirety.[/bold]
  - [textlink="Ban Types and Durations" link="RMCBanTypes"]
  - This game has friendly fire mechanics. Avoid shooting your team.

  ## Zero Tolerance Rules
  You are liable to be banned without warning for breaking these rules.
  - [textlink="Click here to read the zero tolerance rules." link="RMCZeroTolerance"]

  ## Core Game Rules
  These are the general rules of RMC14. Click them for more information.
  - [textlink="1. This is a English server, please only use English." link="RMCLanguage"]
  - [textlink="2. Do not use multiple accounts, or alt accounts." link="RMCMultikey"]
  - [textlink="3. Follow the rules of escalation against non-hostiles." link="RMCRulesEscalation"]
  - [textlink="4. Don't use information gained from outside your character's knowledge." link="RMCMetaknowledge"]
  - [textlink="5. Don't antagonize or harass players." link="RMCKindness"]
  - [textlink="6. Don't quit a command level role without notice." link="RMCRulesCommand"]
  - [textlink="7. Mutinies, riots and similar activity require admin permission." link="RMCMutinies"]
  - 8. Don't quit if you do not get the role/kit/squad you want, be considerate.
  - 9. Follow the roleplay rules and standards of the server. (Outlined at the bottom of this page)

  8. (Additional notes) By opting for certain roles, you are opting into the possibility of supporting any given squad, regardless of personal preference. You are directly affecting the gameplay of others by quitting. Please do not opt into roles you do not feel comfortable playing, so they remain open and obtainable by other players at the start of the round.

  ## Community Rules (All OOC channels)

  - Per the hub rules of SS14, do not speak negatively of other SS14 servers, their community, or staff.

  - Be civil. No harassment/bullying or offensive/abusive/hate speech content that would make the game a hostile space. Avoid political topics.

  - Please do not start heated discussions, including balance issues or roleplay issues, as it is rarely productive with lack of context and information. Missing and new features/fixes and rules can be suggested in the features forum.

  - Do not discuss, complain, or comment about anyone's admin/moderator bans/notes/actions including your own. If you've been banned or disagree with an action, the person involved must make an appeal in our appeals forum where a ruling can be made. It is otherwise assumed that the action is valid and there is no issue.

  ## Command and Military Police

  These rules also apply to any individual who is a MP/Command role (unless they are a member of a hostile force).

  - Command level roles are defined as all department heads, cic staff, MP, and squad leaders.
  - [textlink="1. Command and MP are held to higher standards." link="RMCRulesCommand"]
  - [textlink="2. Command and MP must follow Marine Law." link="RMCMarineLaw"]
  - 3. The goal of MP is to make the server a more immersive and enjoyable place for everyone. Do your best to uphold that goal, by mediating conflicts and assisting the crew and marines with their needs with the minimal force required.

  ## Roleplay Rules and Standards

  - [textlink="1. General Roleplay Standards." link="RMCGeneralRoleplayStandards"]
  - [textlink="2. Character Names." link="RMCCharacterNames"]
  - [textlink="3. Marines." link="RMCMarineRoleplayStandards"]
  - [textlink="4. Command." link="RMCCommandRoleplay"]
  - [textlink="5. Xenonids." link="RMCXenoRoleplay"]
  - [textlink="6. Survivors." link="RMCSurvivorRoleplay"]
  - [textlink="7. Hostile Factions." link="RMCHostileFactionRoleplay"]
</Document>
