<Document>
  # RMC-14 Rules

  [color=#ff0000][bold]If you are unable to click any links, use the in-game guidebook version, in the escape menu.[/bold][/color]

  [italic]RMC is a roleplaying game with team deathmatch elements. This means players are expected, to an extent, to pretend their character is part of this world in their actions and words. This is the intended experience, and the experience the players of RMC enjoy, and is not always about winning.[/italic]

  ## Recent Changes
  Read the relevant sections for the entire text.

  - (General) The Auxiliary Support Officer no longer has authority in requisitions.
  - (General) The Quartermaster has been replaced with the Logistics Officer. All Officer mentions also apply to this new role.
  - [textlink="(Core Rules)" link="RMCKindness"] Split in character crimes into its own section, allowing for more clarity. More information and guidelines have been added.
  - (Current Page) Added Community Rules. These are the same community rules on the Discord.
  - [textlink="(Non-Mod Department SOP)" link="RMCMarineSOPNONModDepartment"] Access Modification.
  - [textlink="(Zero Tolerance)" link="RMCZeroTolerance"] Clarification: Don't share in-game information with anyone playing, neither in-character or any ooc/external means.
  - [textlink="(Core Rule 5)" link="RMCKindness"] Be kind to new players, teach them.
  - [textlink="(Zero Tolerance)" link="RMCZeroTolerance"] External communities should not be promoted or advertised.

  ## Admin Decisions Are Final.
  - Rules are enforced as intended. Every example of a rule break cannot be written, thus enforcement is subject to admin interpretation of the rule's intention.
  - Admins may handle rule breaks through in-character consequences at their discretion. This does not apply to zero tolerance rules, and rule breaks may not be requested to be handled this way.
  - Do not argue with the staff. You may file an appeal if you feel the decision to be incorrect, not ignore it.

  ## Important notes

  ### VPNs

  Heavily avoid using a VPN or any similar program to connect or while connected to RMC. You are putting your account at risk, which may result in your account being permanently banned.
  If you have a legitimate reason to use a VPN, you must attempt at least once to connect to the server without a VPN before requesting an exemption for it.

  ## General Information
  Disconnecting from or ignoring/evading admin-helps will result in action being taken.
  This is to prevent bad actors from avoiding issues. If you need to leave urgently, let us know and it will be considered in your appeal.

  - [bold]These rules are not the same as other servers, should be read in their entirety.[/bold]
  - [textlink="Ban Types and Durations" link="RMCBanTypes"]
  - This game has friendly fire mechanics. Avoid shooting your team.

  ## Zero Tolerance Rules
  You are liable to be banned without warning for breaking these rules.
  - [textlink="Click here to read the zero tolerance rules." link="RMCZeroTolerance"]

  ## Core Game Rules
  These are the general rules of RMC14. Click them for more information.
  - [textlink="1. This is a English server, please only use English." link="RMCLanguage"]
  - [textlink="2. Do not use multiple accounts, or alt accounts, and do not share accounts." link="RMCMultikey"]
  - [textlink="3. Follow the rules of escalation against non-hostiles." link="RMCRulesEscalation"]
  - [textlink="4. Don't use information gained from outside your character's knowledge." link="RMCMetaknowledge"]
  - [textlink="5. Don't antagonize or harass players." link="RMCKindness"]
  - [textlink="6. Don't quit a command level role without notice." link="RMCCommandRoles"]
  - [textlink="7. Mutinies, riots and similar activity require admin permission." link="RMCMutinies"]
  - 8. Don't quit if you do not get the role/kit/squad you want, be considerate.
  - 9. Follow the roleplay rules and standards of the server. (Outlined at the bottom of this page)

  8. (Additional notes) By opting for certain roles, you are opting into the possibility of supporting any given squad, regardless of personal preference. You are directly affecting the gameplay of others by quitting. Please do not opt into roles you do not feel comfortable playing, so they remain open and obtainable by other players at the start of the round.

  ## Community Rules (All OOC channels)

  - Per the hub rules of SS14, do not speak negatively of other SS14 servers, their community, or staff.

  - Be civil. No harassment/bullying or offensive/abusive/hate speech content that would make the game a hostile space. Avoid political topics.

  - Please do not start heated discussions, including balance issues or roleplay issues, as it is rarely productive with lack of context and information. Missing and new features/fixes and rules can be suggested in the features forum.

  - Do not discuss, complain, or comment about anyone's admin/moderator bans/notes/actions including your own. If you've been banned or disagree with an action, the person involved must make an appeal in our appeals forum where a ruling can be made. It is otherwise assumed that the action is valid and there is no issue.

  ## Command and Military Police
  These rules also apply to any individual who is a MP/Command role (unless they are a member of a hostile force).\n[italic]Command roles are defined as; all heads, cic staff, MP, and squad leaders.[/italic]
  - [textlink="1. Command and MP must follow Marine Law." link="RMCMarineLaw"]
  - [textlink="2. Command and MP are held to a higher standard of play." link="RMCHigherStandards"]
  - [textlink="3. MP should try to remain non-lethal and effect arrests, except in specific special circumstances." link="RMCLethalForce"]
  - [textlink="4. MP will be expected to answer for use of lethal force." link="RMCLethalForceConsequences"]
  - Only a whitelisted CO or Provost may pardon a sentence, but appeals can be done. See marine law.

  ## Roleplay Rules and Standards

  - [textlink="1. General Roleplay Standards." link="RMCGeneralRoleplayStandards"]
  - [textlink="2. Character Names." link="RMCCharacterNames"]
  - [textlink="3. Marines." link="RMCMarineRoleplayStandards"]
  - [textlink="4. Command." link="RMCCommandRoleplay"]
  - [textlink="5. Xenonids." link="RMCXenoRoleplay"]
  - [textlink="6. Survivors." link="RMCSurvivorRoleplay"]
  - [textlink="7. Hostile Factions." link="RMCHostileFactionRoleplay"]
</Document>
