<Document>
  ## Command and MP are held to higher standards.

  These rules also apply to any individual who is a MP/Command role (unless they are a member of a hostile force).
  \n\nCommand level roles are defined as all department heads, CIC staff, MP, and squad leaders.

  - You may be rolebanned without warning. This will not usually restrict you from accessing the game.
  - Command and MP must follow [textlink="Marine Law." link="RMCMarineLaw"]

  ## General Rules

  - Be competent in your job and department. Failure to know the basics of your department is liable to result in a role ban to spend more time learning.
  - Do not willingly and openly cooperate with hostile forces.\nSome leeway is given to making deals with hostile forces if the deal benefits the safety or situation of the warship as a whole or crew, and not just yourself.
  - Do not abandon your position to do things unrelated to your role.
  - You are expected to be able to communicate clearly and concisely when communicating on radio channels and announcements, and while in any professional setting.

  ## Disconnecting
  Don't quit without notifying command and sending an Ahelp.
  - If you do not want to play a role, do not opt in for it. Higher importance roles are always selected first, regardless of your role preferences, if nobody else selects them.
  - If you need to leave, use hypersleep to free the slot and also please admin-help your role and that you're leaving.\nThere is no need to wait for a reply after sending the messages.

  ## Non-MP specific

  - Command are at minimum expected to report criminal activity to MP.
  - Executive Officers are expected to have a reasonable understanding of Marine Law and SOP, as they will be involved in it.
  - Do not immediately abandon your subordinates during an attack. Protect the warship and it's crew. Ensure they evacuate safely if evacuation is ordered. It is preferred you ahelp and use hypersleep beforehand if you do not intend to play the hijack portion of the game, so trust is maintained in command level roles from subordinates.

  ### Non-MP During Mutiny

  - Non-MP roles are exempt from following Marine Law to be part of a valid mutiny.

  ## MP Specific

  The goal of MP is to make the server a more immersive and enjoyable place for everyone. Do your best to uphold that goal, by mediating conflicts and assisting the crew and marines with their needs with the minimal force required.


  - MP should try to remain non-lethal unless it is not possible to do so.
  - MP to the best of their ability should be investigating reports of crimes.
  - The MP are not combat roles, and should avoid combat in the area of operations.
  - If your behavior in the Military Police role does not meet community standards, you may be subject to a roleban. This may not be an indication of a bad player, but it is an indication that a player doesn't have the understanding required to play MP.
  - MP is not guaranteed to be a laid-back role. Expect that anything can happen at any point, and you may be required to perform role tasks. Do not select this role otherwise.
  - Be wary of in-character crime rules. Players pushing the line should be reported, but are still expected to be handled in character regardless of outcome.

  ### MP During Mutiny

  - MP are not able to join a mutiny as enemies of the Commander, but may be neutral, in which case they may not help or arrest either side until the mutiny is concluded.
  \nThis applies to the individual player and not the MP department as a whole.

</Document>
