<Document>
  ## Command and MP are held to higher standards.

  These rules also apply to any individual who is a MP/Command role (unless they are a member of a hostile force).

  - Command level roles are defined as all department heads, cic staff, MP, and squad leaders.
  - You may be rolebanned without warning.

  ## General Rules

  - Be competent in your job and department. Failure to know the basics of your department is liable to result in a role ban.
  - Do not willingly and openly cooperate with hostile forces.\nSome leeway is given to making deals with hostile forces if the deal benefits the safety or situation of the ship as a whole and not just yourself.
  - Do not abandon your position to do things unrelated to your role.
  - You are expected to be able to communicate clearly and concisely when communicating on radio channels and announcements, and while in any professional setting.

  ## Non-MP specific

  - Command are at minimum expected to report criminal activity to MP.
  - Executive Officers are expected to have a reasonable understanding of Marine Law and SOP, as they will be involved in it.
  - Only a whitelisted CO or Provost may pardon a sentence, but appeals can be done. See Marine Law.
  - Do not immediately abandon the ship during a raid. Protect the ship and it's crew, don't let hostile forces kill everyone on it without a fight, and ensure they evacuate safely if needed.

  ### Non-MP During Mutiny

  - These roles are exempt from following Marine Law in some cases, if they are correctly part of a valid mutiny.

  ## MP Specific

  The goal of MP is to make the server a more immersive and enjoyable place for everyone. Do your best to uphold that goal, by mediating conflicts and assisting the crew and marines with their needs with the minimal force required.


  - MP should try to remain non-lethal except in specific special circumstances. MP will be expected to answer for use of lethal force.
  - MP to the best of their ability should be investigating reports of crimes, and intervene into criminal activity where possible, unless it conflicts with Marine Law.
  - The MP are not combat roles, and should avoid combat in the area of operations.
  - If your behavior in the Military Police role does not meet community standards, you may be subject to a roleban. This may not be an indication of a bad player, but it is an indication that a player doesn't have the understanding required to play MP.

  ### MP During Mutiny

  - MP are not able to join a mutiny but may be neutral, in which case they may not help or arrest either side until the mutiny is concluded.\nThis applies to the individual player and not the MP as a whole.

  ## Disconnecting
  Don't quit without notifying your supervisor and an admin.
  - If you do not want to play a role, do not opt in for it. Higher ranking roles are always selected first, regardless of role preferences, if nobody else selects them.
  - Command roles help drive rounds. If you need to leave, use hypersleep and please admin-help your role and that you are leaving.
  - There is no need to wait for a reply when admin-helping that you need to disconnect as a head role.

</Document>
