<Document>
  #ZERO TOLERANCE RULES
  You may be banned for any of the below rules with no warning, questioning, or message.

  ### Minimum Age Requirement

  - Players must be at least 16 years of age to play RMC14. Players must be and act at least 16 years old or they will be removed until they are of age, regardless of standing in the community.

  ### End of Round Grief

  - End of round grief (EORG) of your own faction is not permitted and results in an instant unappealable 3 hour ban.\n[bold]This includes suicides without a valid roleplay reason.[/bold]

  - Action will be taken on [bold]any[/bold] friendly fire at round end regardless of who started the griefing, as the round may not be entirely over even if the main condition has been reached.\nDo not return friendly fire at round end, open an ahelp, as this makes it explicitly clear who is griefing.

  ### Sexual content

  - Absolutely [bold]no sexual content[/bold] or [bold]Erotic Roleplay (ERP)[/bold], including direct or indirect mentions of sexual behavior or actions. The server age minimum is 16, minors may be present.\nDo not roleplay romances for this same reason.

  ### Slurs, Racism, etc.

  - Absolutely no hate speech, slurs, bigotry, racism (both real and fictional towards any playable race), sexism, ableism, or any other form of discrimination. This includes using letter substitutions to disguise offensive language or as a "joke".

  [italic](Species have co-existed for many decades, and should be treated as any regular human. Racism RP is not permitted.)[/italic]


  ### Information Fairness

  - Don't share in-game information with anyone playing, neither in-character or any ooc/external means. These rules are in place to ensure a fair and balanced experience for everyone, preventing unfair advantages and ensuring communication remains within the game.
  - Streaming the game in general is allowed, but players in the round should not watch the stream or discuss any current round events to the streamer. As a streamer, please try to make an effort to communicate this.

  ### Ban evasion

  - Attempting to evade game bans will result in an automatic appeal-only permanent ban that is only able to be appealed after six months from the most recent attempt.

  - Attempting to evade job bans through promotions or similar will result in significantly worse bans.

  ### Exploits and External Programs
  - Don't use exploits of bugs or external programs to gain an advantage, or disrupt the server in any way.\nUsing an external program to calculate coordinate locations is permitted.\nUsing an external program to read text on the screen for accessibility purposes is permitted.

  ### Advertising and Spam
  - Do not promote/advertise external communities or servers. Exposure to unmoderated spaces has consistently introduced toxic behavior into our own, harming the healthy culture we work hard to build and maintain. Out-of-character toxicity observed can and should be reported under the context of [textlink="core rule 5." link="RMCKindness"]
</Document>
