<Document>
  #ZERO TOLERANCE RULES
  You may be banned for any of the below rules with no warning.


  - Players must be at least 16 years of age to play RMC14. Players must be and act at least 16 years old or they will be banned until they are of age.

  - End of round grief of your own faction is not permitted and results in an instant unappealable 3 hour ban.\nThis includes suicides without a valid roleplay reason.

  - Action will be taken on [bold]any[/bold] friendly fire at round end regardless of who started the griefing, as the round may not be entirely over even if the main condition has been reached.\nDo not return friendly fire at round end, open an ahelp, as this makes it explicitly clear who is griefing.

  - Absolutely [bold]no sexual content[/bold] or [bold]Erotic Roleplay (ERP)[/bold], including direct or indirect mentions of sexual behavior or actions. The server age minimum is 16, minors may be present.\nDo not roleplay romances for this same reason.

  - Absolutely no hate speech, slurs, bigotry, racism (both real and fictional towards any playable race), sexism, ableism, or any other form of discrimination. This includes using letter substitutions to disguise offensive language or as a "joke".

  [italic](Species have co-existed for many decades, and should be treated as any regular human. Racism RP is not permitted.)[/italic]


  - Don't share in-game or in-character information through external means. Admins are not expected to ensure good faith usage, and any instances may result in actions being taken. This rule is in place to ensure a fair and balanced experience for everyone, preventing unfair advantages and ensuring communication remains within the game.

  - Attempting to evade game bans will result in an automatic appeal-only permanent ban that is only appeal-able after six months and only with a voucher of good behavior from another SS13/SS14 server.

  - Attempting to evade job bans will result in significantly worse bans.

  - Don't use exploits of bugs or external programs to gain an advantage, or disrupt the server in any way.\nUsing an external program to calculate coordinate locations is permitted.\nUsing an external program to read text on the screen for accessability purposes is permitted.
</Document>
