<Document>
  #ZERO TOLERANCE RULES
  You may be banned for any of the below rules with no warning.


  - Players must be at least 16 years of age to play RMC14. Players must be and act at least 16 years old or they will be banned until they are of age.

  - End of round grief of your own faction is not permitted and results in an instant unappealable 3 hour ban.
  - This includes suicides without a valid roleplay reason.

  - We will take action on [bold]any[/bold] friendly fire at round end regardless of who started the griefing, as the round may not be entirely over even if the main condition has been reached.

  - Absolutely no sexual content or Erotic Roleplay (ERP), including direct or indirect mentions of sexual behavior or actions. The server age minimum is 16, minors may be present.

  - Absolutely no hate speech, slurs, bigotry, racism, specism (demeaning other characters in-game due to their in-game race), sexism, disability-related or anything even remotely similar. This includes attempting to substitute letters for a "joke".

  [italic](note: In the lore of RMC14, Nanotrasen workers (and their various humanoid species) have been contracted over to the Marines to build a larger force in exchange for protection of their stations, and have been working for the Marines for a long time. They should be treated as any regular human.)[/italic]


  - Don't communicate in-game/in-character information through methods outside of the game. This is referred to as "Metacomming". Admins will not moderate metacommunication, and will assume it is being abused. (All involved will be actioned on.) This prevents advantages of communication and lack of between allies.

  - Attempting to evade game bans will result in an automatic appeal-only permanent ban that is only appeal-able after six months and only with a voucher of good behavior from another SS13/SS14 server.

  - Attempting to evade job bans will result in an appeal-only permanent ban.

  - Don't use exploits or external programs to play, gain an advantage, or disrupt the server in any way.
</Document>
