<Document>

  # Arresting Procedures
  Should the warship get boarded by a hostile force no arrests should be made unless the person is a danger to the warship and or its personnel.

  ## Officer Ordered Arrests
  Should an Officer ranked UNMC personnel order an arrest for a crime, MPs MUST arrest that person
  - Only the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] [italic](not a [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color])[/italic] and [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] can Officer order an arrest on an MP.
  - They may arrest and hold that person for ten minutes after they have reached the brig while they gather evidence.
  - Should the suspect be declared innocent of all accused crimes, the requesting officer may incur a Prevarication charge. The time for any crimes the suspect committed as a result of the arrest must still be served, however.
  - Before the suspect is detained, the Officer may recind the order.
  - In the case of [bold]officer ordered arrests[/bold] the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may choose to assign an NJP over the initial charge (where valid).

  ## Arresting a Suspect
  [italic]These arrests can be performed anywhere on the warship.[/italic]
  - Take down the Suspect if they resist and securely restrain them.
  - Move the Suspect to a brig cell.
  - Continue to [bold]charging procedure[/bold].

  ## Arresting MP
  - The CMP can only be arrested if approved by the Commander or Provost.
  - Any MPs can only be arrested if approved by the Commander or CMP. The Commander has the final say.
  - A Duty Officer is unable to authorise the arrest of an MP or the CMP.
  - Ensure additional charging of Military Police procedure is followed.


  ## Field Arrests
  [italic]These refer to arrests performed in the area of operations.[/italic]
  - Arrests are restricted to the FOB, dropships, and secure areas unless in pursuit.
  - If a suspect flees outside the above areas or are witnessed by the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color], they may be pursuited.
  - If there are hostiles in the vicinity, the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must abort the arrest and move to a secure area.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s may move between secure areas.
  - Squad Leaders may detain marines of their squad that violate the law, but must detain marines of their squad by orders of the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] or Command.
  - Marines detained by the Squad Leaders should be passed onto the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] when possible.

  ## Victims May Drop Charges
  - Excluding capital crimes, neglect of duty, and grievous bodily harm, the victim of a crime retains the right to drop charges.
  - This is permitted after the defendant is moved to a secure location or the brig.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must release the defendant, with continued arrest attempts for the original crime being considered prevarication.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may hold the defendant for no longer than [bold]5 minutes[/bold] if they wish to contact Provost Marshal Office to appeal.
  - If an appeal to arrest from Provost Marshal Office is not recieved within the 5 minutes, the defendant must be released.

</Document>
