<Document>

  # Arresting Procedures
  Should the warship get boarded by a hostile force, no arrests should be made unless the person presents a danger to the warship and/or its personnel.

  - Any orders given by any personnel who are legally detained or facing charges are considered void until the charges are cleared, the brig time is served, or the detention is resolved.

  ## Officer Ordered Arrests
  Should an Officer of the UNMC order an arrest for a crime, MPs MUST arrest that person.
  - Only the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] [italic](not a [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color])[/italic] and [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] can Officer order an arrest on an MP.
  - They may arrest and hold that person for ten minutes after they have reached the brig while they gather evidence.
  - Should the suspect be declared innocent of all accused crimes, the requesting officer may incur a Prevarication charge. The time for any crimes the suspect committed as a result of the arrest must still be served, however.
  - Before the suspect is detained, the Officer may rescind the order.
  - In the case of [bold]officer ordered arrests[/bold] the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may choose to assign an NJP over the initial charge (where valid).

  ## Arresting a Suspect
  [italic]These arrests can be performed anywhere on the warship.[/italic]
  - Take down the Suspect if they resist and securely restrain them.
  - Move the Suspect to a holding cell.
  - Continue to [bold]charging procedure[/bold].

  ## Arresting MP
  - The [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] can only be arrested if approved by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] or [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color].
  - Any [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s can only be arrested if approved by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] or [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color]. The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] has the final say.
  - A [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color] is unable to authorise the arrest of an [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] or the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color].
  - Ensure additional charging of Military Police procedure is followed.

  ## Actions Against the Commander
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must contact [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] before taking any law-related actions against the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color].
  - If there is no [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] of the operation may be arrested, but [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] must be notified after the fact, through fax.


  ## Field Arrests
  [italic]These refer to arrests performed in the area of operations.[/italic]
  - Field arrests are restricted to the [bold]FOB[/bold], dropships, and secure areas unless in pursuit.
  - If a suspect flees outside the above areas or are witnessed by the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color], they may be pursued.
  - If there are hostiles in the vicinity, the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must abort the arrest and move to a secure area.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s may move between secure areas.
  - [bold]Squad Leaders[/bold] may detain marines of their squad that violate the law, but must detain marines of their squad by orders of the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color], [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], or any commisioned officer. This may also apply to personnel that are deploying unauthorised.
  - Marines and personnel detained by the [bold]Squad Leaders[/bold] should be passed onto the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] in a secure area when possible.

  ## Victims May Drop Charges
  - Excluding capital crimes, neglect of duty, and grievous bodily harm, the victim of a crime retains the right to drop charges.
  - This is permitted after the defendant is moved to a secure location or the brig.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must release the defendant on the victim's request, with continued arrest attempts for the original crime being considered prevarication.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may hold the defendant for no longer than [bold]5 minutes[/bold] if they wish to contact [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] to appeal the arrest against the victim's wishes.
  - If an appeal to arrest from [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] is not received within the 5 minutes, the defendant must be released.


  ## Self Defense or Defense of Others
  Charges are not to be applied to those who use force on others when defending themselves from illegal harm, so long as they defend themselves with proportional force. This also extends to the defense of others if they believe the others are in lethal danger. This does not apply to lawful killings such as executions.


  The person being attacked should only use proportional lethal force until the person is no longer able to attack, and look to get away from the attacker where possible to alert the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]. The person being attacked should notify the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] or their supervisor about the use of self-defense.

  Examples of proportional force are;
  - Punching when being punched.
  - Melee weapons when being attacked with melee weapons.
  - Bullets against bullets.

</Document>
