<Document>
  # Executions

  ## Authorization
  - Executions are limited to prisoners who have committed crimes with execution as a possible punishment.
  - They must be authorized by the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color].
  - In the event the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] is absent, [bold]BOTH[/bold] the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] and [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] must give the authorization.
  - A [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color] is unable to authorize an execution.
  - Executions may be delayed if the alert level is RED or DELTA.
  - A prisoner that is permanently confined may request to be executed in place of their confinement, but must still be authorized.

  ## Authorized methods of execution
  Authorized methods of execution must be used in executions and are listed below.
  - Lethal injection handled by the current [bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold].
  - Firing squad by the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] or [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]. This must be done with standard issue firearms, and not with explosives or weapons considered cruel. The [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may permit only the victims of the prisoner's crimes to join the firing line.

  ## Procedure
  - The [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] [bold]MUST[/bold] make a ship-wide announcement informing the crew of the intent to execute, the reason/crime, and the execution method.

  [italic]None of the below steps should each exceed 5 minutes to fully process, otherwise they may be skipped if the prisoner was warned prior to the time expiring.[/italic]

  - The prisoner may request a tobacco product, and a food and drink as a last meal. The items should be reasonably acquirable, else they should be provided an alternative.
  - The prisoner may request a blindfold for the execution if available.
  - Up to three people may be requested by the prisoner to view the execution.
  - The prisoner is given a chance to give final words. The prisoner may use the radio for this.
  - The execution may proceed.



</Document>
