<Document>
  # Definitions

  [italic]These definitions are used throughout the rest of Marine Law.[/italic]

  [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]
  - The official UNMC Commanding Officer of the ship.
  - Anything with the words [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] only applies to the current whitelisted Commanding Officer of the ship. These rights can be transferred to any UNMC Officers that are ranked [bold]Major[/bold] or above by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].

  \n

  [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]
  - The current [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] of an operation.
  - Transferable to a new [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], per the [textlink="Commander Succession" link="RMCCommandChain"].

  If the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] is rendered incapable of command [bold]temporarily[/bold], the [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color] inherits [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] rights, but should the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] return, they are still the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]. This includes but is not limited to:

  - Prolonged communications outage.
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] deploying in the field.

  If the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] is rendered [bold]permanently[/bold] incapable of command, the next in the [textlink="Commander Succession" link="RMCCommandChain"] becomes the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], rather than becoming a [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color]. This includes but is not limited to:
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] is relieved of duty due to [bold]arrest[/bold] or [bold]mutiny[/bold].
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] becoming [bold]unrevivable[/bold].

  Ensure when assigning a new [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], that this is announced. Include the new [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]'s name and the reason for them being assigned as the new [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], to avoid confusion.

  \n

  [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color]
  - The ranking officer in the [textlink="Commander Succession" link="RMCCommandChain"] who, in the temporary absence of the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], is placed in command of the warship.
  - Unless explicitly stated otherwise, the [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color] is interchangeable with, and inherits the rights of [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] in this case.

  \n

  [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color]
  - The Chief of Military Police, assigned to the warship.
  - Only transferable to the [bold]Warden[/bold] by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], if another [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] is appointed to be the acting [bold]Warden[/bold] in their place.
  - An acting [bold]Warden[/bold] cannot be the acting [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color]
  - A deputized person may not be the acting [bold]Warden[/bold].

  \n

  [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]
  - Military Police, including personnel validly deputized by the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], who deal with Marine Law.

  \n

  [bold]Officer[/bold]
  - A person who is a Commissioned Officer. These rights cannot be transferred.
  - A person who is a Warrant Officer. These rights cannot be transferred.

  \n

  [bold]Department heads[/bold]
  - A person who is responsible for an entire department, which includes the [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold], [bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold], [bold]Auxiliary Support Officer[/bold], [bold]Logistics Officer[/bold], [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color].

  \n

  [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold]
  - Standard personnel whose main duties are within CIC. This includes the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], [bold]Executive Officer[/bold], and [bold]Staff Officers[/bold].

  \n

  [bold]Flight Crew[/bold]
  - Designated Pilots and Dropship Crew Chiefs.

  \n

  [bold]Aiding, abetting, conspiring[/bold]
  - Assisting others in committing a crime, directly or indirectly, encouraging them to commit one (including bribery), conspiring or attempting to commit a crime will be treated as having committed that crime with regards to punishment.

  \n

  [bold]Lawful Orders[/bold]
  - Personnel are required to follow all lawful orders from their superiors and are NOT-required to follow unlawful orders.
  - If personnel are refusing to follow an order, they must state why they believe it would break Marine Law, making it an unlawful order.
  - Valid NJPs are not unlawful orders in the case of neglected duties.

  \n

  [bold]Riot equipment[/bold]
  - Flashbangs.
  - Teargas.
  - Riot shotguns with beanbag rounds.
  - Riot shields and armor.
  - Riot grenade launchers.
  - Rubber bullets.

  \n

  [bold]FOB[/bold]
  - The Forward Operating Base.
  - Designated by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]. It is a reinforced area, usually being the primary landing zone.
  - FOBs do not have to be placed adjacent to a landing zone. However, the primary landing zone itself must at least be properly defended and guarded.

  \n

  [bold]Area of Operations (AO)[/bold]
  - The area of operations is the broad location where personnel are being deployed to conduct an operation.

  \n

  [bold]Secure Areas[/bold]
  - Must be designated by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] or staff officers. It is a reinforced area, where there has been no recent combat or threats.
  - The [bold]FOB[/bold] is usually a secure area until it is attacked, for example.
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] or any [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold] at any point may designate an area no longer secure.
  - Areas that have been recently attacked are presumed no longer secure, and should be reported for safety.

  \n

  [bold]Field Hospital[/bold]
  - Must be designated by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] or [bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold]. It is a reinforced area, where there has been no recent combat or threats.
  - It is the only area aside from the [bold]FOB[/bold] that the [bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold] or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may give permission to doctors and nurses to move to.
  - It must be designated as a [bold]Secure Area.[/bold]

  \n

  [bold]Alert Levels[/bold]
  - Code [bold][color=lightgreen]Green[/color][/bold]: All clear.
  - Code [bold][color=lightblue]Blue[/color][/bold]: Potentially hostile activity on board.
  - Code [bold][color=red]Red[/color][/bold]: There is an immediate threat to the ship or it's crew. Examples of usage include; AI Core Security issue, biohazard containment breach, general quarters. Distress beacon, evacuation, and usage of sentry systems authorized.
  - Code [bold][color=black]Delta[/color][/bold]:  Immediately applies if the warship hull has a major breach by intruders. An order of evacuation, self-destruction, or hold of the warship will be made at this time.

  \n

  [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color]
  - Hold significant weight on how Marine Law is handled in their operational areas.
  - In the event that Marine Law is being mishandled aboard a UNMC warship or within the AO of a UNMC warship, [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] may see fit to dispatch personnel.
  - Members of the [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] obey only their direct superiors and are not beholden to Marine command or officers.
  - Provost [bold]Marshals[/bold] are not required to follow Marine Law.
  - Provost [bold]Inspectors[/bold] and above are the final word on Marine Law in their AO.
  - Provost [bold]Advisors[/bold] do not hold any direct authority themselves, however they are expected to ensure Marine Law is correctly handled.
</Document>
