<Document>
  # Prisoner Rights
  This is a list of rights prisoners have.
  - They cannot be denied, with the exception of radio access, except in extreme situations with authorization from the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]. Prisoners can fax [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] to have their rights be given back.

  ## Common Space
  All prisoners are permitted to enter the common space by default.
  - Permabrigged prisoners do not have this right, but can be given access with an escort for good behavior.

  This right can be lost in the event of:
  - Mutiny, riots, emergencies
  - Jailbreaking
  - Commiting a crime within the brig. If this happens, the right can be given back by the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].

  ## Protection and Medical Treatment
   - If there are prisoners, a member of the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must remain in the brig at all times except if the only prisoners are in permanent confinement or there is an emergency.
  - Prisoners must be kept safe and unharmed.
  - A surgical tray is to remain within the brig at all times, unless there is an emergency.
  - Treatment should take place within the brig when possible. If not, an [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must escort the prisoner to the medbay and watch over them while they are treated.
  - Prisoners must receive medical aid if needed.
  - Prisoners must be revived unless they have been legally executed.
  - Self-harm may result in being constrained for the duration of the sentence.

  ## Access to a Radio
  Prisoners are authorized a standard headset with the common channel.
  - If any [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] believes that it is being abused, they can revoke this right after a clear warning of the behavior.
  - Prisoners may appeal this.
  - Prisoners may have their radio revoked if a mutiny is active until the mutiny is over.

  ## Clothing
  - Prisoners must be allowed either the brig orange uniform, or their original uniform if none are available.
  - Prisoners must be allowed footwear.

</Document>
