<Document>
  # CO Provisions and Regulations

  ## Arrest Immunity
  The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] is not above marine law. However, they may not be arrested without the permission of [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color].
  - Should a [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] break marine law, [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] must be contacted through fax to arrest the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color].
  - The right to contact [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] may not be denied.
  - If the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] has been deposed due to mutiny, the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] are to treat them the same as a deposed [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] per [bold]special provisions[/bold], lose their arrest immunity, and are no longer considered the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].

  ## Execution Privileges
  The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], High Command, and [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] Marshals may perform [bold]Battlefield Executions[/bold]. They may [bold]personally[/bold] execute any person who marine law applies to, as long as they are under their authority, without warning or procedure, unless the person is already in [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] custody.

  To perform a [bold]Battlefield Execution[/bold], one of the following conditions must be fulfilled;
  - They are a threat to your command. Credibly attempting to undermine or remove your command by illegal means.\nInsults, disagreements, or being reported to the [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] are not valid reasons. Countermanding or refusing to follow orders are.
  - They are threat to others. Credibly threatening and attempting to do harm to the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], or someone while in the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]'s presence.
  - They are a threat to the ship or the operation. Credibly threatening or attempting to do damage to the ship, the UNMC, or operation while in the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]'s presence.

  ## Escort Missions
  The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] has two escort provisions they may order, not to be confused with [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] [bold]FOB[/bold] protection within the SOP. There must be a minimum of a single [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] aboard the ship at all times, per the SOP.
  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may appoint up to two [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s as [bold]Honor Guards[/bold] for personal protection while in the AO. They are permitted to fight in the frontline with the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]. [bold]Executive Officer[/bold]s must request permission from the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] to do the same.
  - [bold]Honor Guard[/bold]s may be given Honor Guard kits during their duty.
  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may request any amount of [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s to escort non-combat personnel planetside, provided they avoid the frontline at all costs. This includes a [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] who will not be going to fight at the frontline.

  Should the escorted individual be incapacitated, the escorting [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s must try to recover the individual. If this is no longer possible, they must return shipside.

  During an escort mission, the following rules must be followed by all parties;
  - The escorting [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s must focus keeping the escorted individual secure at all times and not enforce marine law.
  - The escorting [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s must remain in line of sight to the escorted individual at all times to the best of their ability. The escorted individual may not order the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] to do something that would put them outside line of sight.

  ## Pardons
  The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may pardon criminals by name and crime they are being pardoned for if they believe it is in the best interests of the operation.
  - Only minor and major crimes may be pardoned.
  - Capital crimes may not be pardoned except with the permission of [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color].
  - The [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color], or if absent, an [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may appeal these pardons to [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color], and if they believe the pardon was wrongfully done.
  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may be held responsible for further criminal actions committed by those they pardon.
  - If [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] reverses the decision of the pardon, the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] must ensure the prisoner returns to serve their time without failure. Failure to do so may result in removal from command and charges at the discretion of [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color].
  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] must know the crimes committed, and announce the name of the prisoner, and the reason why they are being pardoned.
  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] does not need to be present for the release of the prisoner.

  ## Revoking Arrests
  The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may also invoke pardoning authority to revoke arrests, or warrants of arrests, for a person before they are placed in the brig.
  - This revocation follows the same procedure as pardons.
  - They must be announced the same way.
  - They are subject to the same appeals to [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color].
  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] is responsible for the actions of the person being pardoned.
  - If the person whose arrest was revoked reoffends, removal from command and charges may apply to the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] by the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] with permission from [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color].

  These conditions must be true for the revocation to be valid;
  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] is in the general vicinity as the person being arrested.
  - The revocation is not being used on a person who are in the process of committing a crime, are resisting or have resisted arrest, or are already in the brig. (In which case a regular pardon can be used.)
  - The revocation is not being used to prevent an arrest authorized by [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color].

  ## Demotions
  The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may demote or discharge UNMC personnel under their authority if the person has commited [bold]any[/bold] major crime, and not only major crimes with demotion listed as a punishment. The demotion should fit the severity, and also remain within the department they were originally working. An engineer should not be demoted into a medical position.

  ## General NJPs
  The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may issue NJPs at any point they find a person's behavior inappropriate or contrary to good order, and conduct deserving of punishment even if a crime has not been committed, such as acting in an unprofessional manner, failing to complete a job in satisfactory conditions, or failing to uphold standards of good order.
  - All NJP conditions and rights apply when this provision is invoked, including a 10 minute brig sentence if refused.

  ## Deputizing
  The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may deputize the following personnel to make arrests and enforce marine law, should [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s be unavailable or unable to respond in a timely manner. When deputized, these personnel are expected and required to follow Marine Law like an [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color], and will carry the same punishments.
  - The Executive Officer.
  - The Auxiliary Support Officer.
  - Staff Officers.
  - UNMC Synthetics.

  ## Commanding Officer Regulations

  These regulations are not modifiable without approval from [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color].

  [bold]Uniforms[/bold]

  - [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]s must remain in UNMC uniform at all times.
  - Anything in their personal dress vendors, as well as standard UNMC enlisted and officer uniforms are acceptable.
  - They should avoid wearing department uniforms.
  - Dress clothing, swimwear, sleepwear, civilian clothing, and athletic wear should be reserved for their appropriate recreational, training activities or situations.
  - They should never be found bare or in underwear in public appearances.
  - Wearing the uniform of any other military or organization is strictly prohibited.

  [bold]Conduct[/bold]

  - [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]s are role models for those under their command.
  - They must exhibit dress, behavior, and mentality fitting of their rank and decades of service.
  - They must demonstrate level-headedness, maturity, and competence.
  - While not expected to be humorless and strict, they should maintain reasonable dignity.

</Document>
