<Document>
  # Right to Appeal
  - Accepting an NJP waives the right to appeal.
  - Appeals are used to correct errors, but may not be used to add new charges or punishments if a brig timer was already set.
  - Appeals must be handled before executions, demotions, and NJPs. Appealing prisoners should have their brig timers set and running while the appeal is being processed.
  - Personnel may be placed in holding awaiting their appeal if it had no brig sentence.
  - Whomever is handling the appeal has the final say in the outcome of the appeal.

  ## Appeal a Sentence in a timely manner
  If an appeal process has not started within 10 minutes, or 30 minutes for permanently brigged, after a request to appeal has been clearly communicated to any [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color], [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color], or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color];
  - The prisoner must be released.
  - The person who received the request, if failing to take appropriate action, are to be given a [bold]Neglect of Duty[/bold] charge.

  ## Who can handle an appeal
  - Anyone under the jurisdiction of marine law has the right to appeal their punishment to their choice of either the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] or the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]. If the chosen person is involved in the crime, they must delegate to an uninvolved [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] or [bold]Officer[/bold]. This delegation can also be done for any other reason.

  Ideally, these people should not be handling the appeal;
  - Witnesses/victims.
  - Anyone who ordered the arrest.
  - The person who set the charges or punishment.

  ## Appeal outcomes
  A charge cannot be removed by appeal if the prisoner is found guilty, however, the person who handles the appeal can process the appeal as;
  - A valid charge, no modification.
  - Modify the charge to a lower charge.
  - Reduce the punishment of a charge up to the minimum punishment.
  - Remove a charge the prisoner is found innocent for.

  ## Suspending Appeals
  Appeals may be postponed in these situations;
  - Threats requiring evacuation.
  - A hostile force approaching or onboard the ship.
  - Riots or jailbreaks.
  - The prisoner requiring medical treatment and is not conscious.
  - There being an already processing appeal.
  - The prisoner having escaped or is unreachable in person.

  Appeals may not be suspended for these examples;
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] and [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] being busy with other tasks.
  - The prisoner being declared insane.

  ## Appeals Procedure
  - The appeal processor must be present and in person.
  - The charges should be listed along with their punishment one by one. This may be done by any [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] or the appeal processor.
  - A discussion including witness accounts, the story of the accused, evidence, and mitigating circumstances is recommended.
  - If charges were applied incorrectly they must be removed. No new charges may be added as a result if a brig time has been set.
  - An appeal outcome should be given for each listed charge individually.
  - The final punishment should be for the remaining crimes.
  - The appeal processor decides the outcome. They may not be ordered or forced otherwise.
  - The appeal processor cannot be retaliated against by anyone for any part of the appeal, unless it is a neglect of duty charge due to the appeal procedure not being followed correctly.


  ## Appeals to the Provost Marshal Office
  - The prisoner may request another appeal to the [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color].
  - This may be done if their appeal is denied, or done instead of a standard appeal.
  - If the [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] does not reply to the appeal in 10 minutes, the appeal is considered denied.
  - The prisoner must be provided a pen and paper to write a fax to the [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color].
  - If the prisoner is a threat to themself or others if unrestrained, they have the right to dictate the fax and have it written by any [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color].

</Document>
