<Document>
  # Special Provisions

  ## Medical Experiments
  A prisoner may waive their rights to participate in medical experiments. Researchers performing approved medical experiments  may not be held liable for damages inflicted on the subject within the approved paramaters of the experiment.
  - All experiments require the signed (or stamped) approval of either the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] (But not [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color]) or the CMO.
  - Prisoners can request to be used as subjects. The prisoner's brig time must continue to run while they are being used, and are free to go when it expires and are not obligated to continue.
  - Medical experiments that will result in death must only be offered to prisoners who are to be executed, or if execution is one of the listed punishment options for their crime. It is otherwise illegal, and will result in a [bold]Attempted Murder[/bold], or [bold]Murder[/bold] charge where relevant.

  ## MP Involvement in Mutinies
  - Attempting to overthrow the legitimate command staff is illegal, and [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must do everything in their power to prevent it.
  - Should a mutiny be sucessful, resulting in the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] being deposed or surrendering, [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] should hold the former [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] in indefinite confinement if their freedom would reignite the conflict.
  - The [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color] may be optionally skipped in the chain of command, if the mutiny is successful.
  - MP will after resume normal operations with the new commander, and any subterfuge charges, sedition charges, insubordination charges, and ordered arrests in relation to the original commander must be dropped.

  ## Actions Against the Commander
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must contact [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] before taking any law-related actions against the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color].
  - If there is no [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] of the operation may be arrested, but [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] must be notified after the fact, through fax.

  ## Self defense or Defense of Others
  Charges are not to be applied to those who use force on others when defending themselves from illegal harm, so long as they defend themselves with proportional force. This also extends to the defense of others if they believe the others are in lethal danger. This does not apply to lawful killings such as executions.


  The person being attacked should only use proportional lethal force until the person is no longer able to attack, and look to get away from the attacker where possible to alert the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]. The person being attacked should notify the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] or their supervisor about the use of self-defense.

  Examples of proportional force are;
  - Punching when being punched.
  - Melee weapons when being attacked with melee weapons.
  - Bullets against bullets.

  ## Emergencies
  - In emergencies, such as significant boardings or a compromised brig, imprisoned personnel may be released by the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color], if they believe they will not be a further threat or hinderance during the emergency, also particularly if they display good behavior.
  - If the imprisoned are too dangerous or detrimental to the survival of the crew, they should be escorted to an escape pod by a commissioned officer or an [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] who will maintain their safety.
  - A simple red alert is not sufficent reason for release, unless the ship is significantly overrun.

</Document>
