<Document>
  #Drone, Tier 1
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMXenoDrone"/>
  ##Playing as a Drone
  Drones are the core of any Hive, a versatile caste that can perform many of the critical tasks needed to keep a Hive running smoothly. As Drones are the first caste unlocked for evolution each round, they often form the backbone of the initial efforts to build up a Hive in anticipation of the coming round.

  Drones are well suited to being a starter caste for new Xeno players, as they have the tools necessary to introduce players to building, supporting the team, and basic backline support. Drones should strive to avoid combat where possible unless it's part of a larger strategy, as they lack the means to defend themselves against most threats.

  ##Abilities:
  - [bold]Plant Weeds[/bold]: Places a resin node which spreads weeds across a large area. Weeds are essential for controlling space and allow the Hive to build resin structures.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoPlantWeeds"/>
  - [bold]Choose Resin Structure[/bold]: Chooses what resin structure to make, to then be used by Secrete Resin. When creating solid structures, Drones only have access to standard (Non-thick) Resin variants.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoChooseResinStructure"/>
  - [bold]Secrete Resin[/bold]: Secretes the chosen resin structure on any tile you click, provided it has weeds.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoSecreteResin"/>
  - [bold]Order Construction[/bold]: Orders the construction of a [textlink="Hive Structure" link="RMCGuideHiveStructures.xml"].
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoOrderConstruction" Caption=""/>
  - [bold]Transfer Plasma[/bold]: Transfers plasma from yourself to a sister, provided you both remain still.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoTransferPlasma"/>
  - [bold]Weak Corrosive Acid[/bold]: Secretes a glob of weak acid on items or structures to be dissolved at the cost of Plasma.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoCorrosiveAcid"/>
  - [bold]Emit Pheromones[/bold]: Emits one of the three pheromones to provide buffs to yourself and nearby Xenos. The strength of pheromones is dependent on caste and does not stack with pheromones of the same type.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoPheromones" Caption=""/>

  ##Additional Information:

  - As a Drone, you'll be able to carry out a lot of the basic tasks required to transform colony structures into Xenonid Hives. Use your weak corrosive acid to melt windows, airlocks, obstructing furniture, and any items that could be useful to Survivors or Marines. When building, try to design areas with Xenos in mind - always try to build doorways at least two tiles wide, and avoid building narrow hallways or 1-tile chokes that can cause traffic jams. Above all, remember to weed everywhere you can! The more weeds, the better.

  - Drones are able to provide basic support in managing captures and preparing for infections. All Drones (even lessers!) are able to pick up and plant eggs from the Queen on Hive Weeds, which can be used to infect a Host after a short growth time. Drones can also pick up Parasites from egg morphers or eggs and place them into resin holes or use them to infect stunned or restrained hosts. Be quick if using Parasites in this way, as they die if they're outside a safe 'home' for 30 seconds.

</Document>
