<Document>
  # Heavy Grenadier Specialist: "Michael Bay Fan"

  ## Ordnance Dominance
  Difficulty: [color=#FF8C00]Hard[/color]

  When the marines need a rapid, explosive push or fortified positions cleared, the Heavy Grenadier Specialist is the premier choice.
  Wielding the M83 Grenade Launcher, this specialist delivers a versatile payload of grenades with greater precision and range than standard methods, capable of turning the tide with overwhelming explosive force.

  ## Standard Issue Kit
  The standard issue for a Heavy Grenadier includes:
  <Box> <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WeaponLauncherM83"/> </Box>
  The M83 Grenade Launcher is an advanced ordnance delivery system, distinguished by its [bold]six-shot capacity[/bold] coupled with [color=#00FF00]IFF feature[/color].
  This IFF system allows grenade projectiles fired from the M83 to [italic]safely pass through friendly marines[/italic] without hitting any, ensuring the ordnance can reach its intended target point even in crowded friendly engagements.
  <Box>  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCArmorM3G4"/> <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCArmorHelmetM3G4"/></Box>
  This specialized combat ensemble grants the Grenadier [italic]heavy-class armor protection[/italic], effectively mitigating ballistic, explosive, and general trauma damage.
  Crucially, it achieves this robust defense while imposing only [italic]medium armor movement speed penalties[/italic], maintaining good battlefield agility. The included Helmet also allows the user to deflect 6 parasites.

  ## Tactical Employment: The Resilient Nuisance

  The  Grenadier operates as a heavily armored point man or a durable fire support element. Your incredible survivability allows you to draw fire and hold positions others cannot, while your Grenade Launcher provides crucial stun and burst damage against priority targets.

  <Box>[bold]Playing to Your Strengths:[/bold]</Box>
  -   [bold]Anti-Carrier Operations[/bold]: Leverage your helmet's facehugger resistance to aggressively engage.
  -   [bold]High-Value Target Disruption[/bold]: Focus your Grenade Launcher fire on high-priority threats like Prae's, Ravagers, or dense packs of warriors. The ability to stunlock these targets can create critical openings for your team.
  -   [bold]Breaching and Spearheading Pushes[/bold]: Your grenades are not just for engaging hostiles; they are potent tools for reshaping the battlefield. Utilize your explosive ordnance to [italic]breach enemy fortifications, destroy barricades, and blow open new pathways.[/italic] allowing your squad to push through the opening, creating space for your squadmates to follow and exploit the new access point.
  -   [bold]Resin Clearing Specialist[/bold]: HEDP grenades excel at clearing vast amounts of sticky resin. Use this capability to pave the way for swift marine advances.

  <Box>[bold]Mitigating Weaknesses & Conserving Fire:[/bold]</Box>
  -   [color=#FFD700][bold]HIGH-TIER RESISTANCE[/bold]: Be aware that formidable Xenomorphs like [bold]Crushers and the Queen possess significant resistance to explosive damage and effects[/bold]. Do not expect standard HEDP spam to be highly effective against these elite threats. They will likely shrug off much of the damage and head for you.[/color]
  -   [bold]Extreme Ammunition Conservatism[/bold]: Every grenade must count. Do not expend ordnance on trivial targets or situations where other marines can effectively engage. Your grenades are a precious resource best saved for critical moments or high-value targets that *only you* can effectively stun or burst down.
  -   [bold]Friendly Fire is Critical[/bold]: [color=#FF0000]Your grenades are indiscriminate and can easily wipe out a friendly push.[/color] Never fire into groups of marines. Careful shot placement is paramount.
  -   [bold]Strategic Combinations[/bold]: Don't rely on a single grenade type. Alternate between HEDP for stuns, HIDP for area denial, and HEFA for specific, clear high-damage opportunities. Stunning xenos with HEDP can create openings for more devastating follow-ups.
  -   [color=#FF0000][bold]BEWARE GRENADES BOUNCE![/bold][/color] [bold]Always ensure a clear line of sight for your grenades. Firing at an awkward angle near a wall or obstacle can cause your grenade to bounce back towards your position or, even worse, directly into your advancing squadmates. Double-check your trajectory before every shot, especially in confined spaces.[/bold]

  ## The Enduring Challenge: Vigilance & Adaptability

  The Grenadier's greatest long-term threats are complacency and a static battlefield. While initially feeling god like in your resilience, remember that Xenomorphs adapt and the nature of warfare evolves.

  Overconfidence, bred from shrugging off early encounters, can lead to reckless positioning-exposing your known vulnerabilities or underestimating coordinated assaults.
  True mastery of this kit lies not in its raw tankiness, but in disciplined play, respecting your limitations (especially ammunition) and constantly adapting your tactics.

  The Grenadier is a powerful role, but even "gods" can fall if they believe their own legend too much and fail to see the shifting sands of the battlefield. Stay vigilant, play smart, and your legend might just endure.

</Document>
