<Document>
  [bold]WESTON-YAMADA CORPORATION[/bold]
  [color=#FFFFFF]░░░░░░░░[/color][color=#d16d1f]█[/color][color=#eb7a23]▌[color=#FFFFFF]░░░░[/color]▄███▌[color=#25b266]▌▄[/color][color=#1c8a4e]█▀[/color]▄██████████[/color]
  [color=#FFFFFF]░░░░░░░░[/color][color=#d16d1f]█[/color][color=#eb7a23]▌[color=#FFFFFF]░░[/color]▄██[color=#d16d1f]██[/color]█▌[color=#1c8a4e]█▀[/color]▄██[color=#d16d1f]█▀[/color][/color]
  [color=#FFFFFF]░░░░░░░░[/color][color=#d16d1f]█[/color][color=#eb7a23]▌▄██[color=#d16d1f]█▀[/color][color=#1c8a4e]▄[/color][color=#d16d1f]▐[/color]█▌▄██[color=#d16d1f]█▀[/color][color=#EEEE]▄[/color]▐████████[/color]
  [color=#FFFFFF]░░░░░░░░[/color][color=#d16d1f]█[/color][color=#eb7a23]██[color=#d16d1f]█▀[/color][color=#25b266]▄█[/color][color=#1c8a4e]█[/color][color=#d16d1f]▐[/color]███[color=#d16d1f]█▀[/color][color=#EEEEEE]▄█[/color][color=#DDDDDD]█[/color][/color]
  [color=#FFFFFF]░░░░░░░░[/color][color=#d16d1f]██▀[/color][color=#25b266]▄█[/color][color=#1c8a4e]█▀[/color][color=#FFFFFF]░[/color][color=#d16d1f]▐██▀[/color][color=#EEEEEE]▄█[/color][color=#DDDDDD]█▀▐[/color][color=#eb7a23]▐████████[/color]
  [bolditalic]"THE FUTURE IS NOW"[/bolditalic]
  [color=#383838]▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄[/color]
  [color=#eb7a23]▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀[/color]

  # Corporate Liaison Guide
  [italic] By SharkSnake98 on GitHub[italic]

  ## Introduction and Information
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookRoleLiaisonYou"/>
  </Box>

  Welcome to the [bold][color=#eb7a23]Weston[/color]-[color= #25b266]Yamada[/color] Corporation[/bold]! You have chosen to become a member of the Special Services Division as a Liaison; our representatives, sent afar to make sure that our interests are maintained and protected. However, that can feel vague and confusing, especially to Jr. Executives who aren’t yet acclimatized to the expectations and duties of the role. This guide is intended to fix that, by developing a set of Do’s and Don’ts, as well as establishing expectations and highlighting the resources you have access to.


  ## Don’ts
  This section comprises various actions you generally should try to avoid while working as a Corporate Liaison, as they are either bad form, not advised, generally illegal, or all of the above!

  ### Don’t: Be Antagonistic
  Your job as a [bold]Corporate Liaison[/bold] is not only to make sure WeYa reaps a profit, but also to ensure that our relations between us and the [color=#1b67a5][bold]UN[/bold][/color] are maintained, and kept amicable, at the very least. While you should always try to ensure our interests are maintained, you shouldn’t try to cause significant interference during a UNMC operation; although you don’t necessarily need to be friendly to them, you should never be overtly antagonistic, unless specified otherwise by an Admin.

  [bold][color=#eb7a23]We[/color][color=#25b266]Ya[/color][/bold] and the [color=#1b67a5][bold]UN[/bold][/color] are allies, and their success during an operation is almost always a positive for the Company. Besides, if there’s any issues, you can always send us a fax.

  ### Don’t: Engage in Frontline Combat
  To put it bluntly, you are not a combat role; you struggle to aim a firearm larger than a pistol, and you cannot wear most armor except for emergency gear. Your job usually consists of filing paperwork, liaising with the marines, and generally engaging in roleplay. While you are free to head down planetside, it’s advisable you stay in the [bold]FOB[/bold] at most times. After all, the Company needs its Liaisons alive to protect our interests.

  ### Don’t: Drink Yourself to Death
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCDrinkAlcoholSake" Caption="Drink"/>  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMDrinkCanBeerLite" Caption="in"/> <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMDrinkCanAle" Caption="moderation!"/>
  </Box>
  As the Almayer’s [bold]Corporate Liaison[/bold], you have access to a collection of different alcoholic and non-alcoholic drinks inside your closet. Though it may be tempting to overindulge, this is [bold]NEVER[/bold] a good idea. Not only do you risk suffering from alcohol poisoning if you drink too much, diverting medical assets away from the operation, but it could result in your imprisonment, and is terrible for PR.

  A [bold][color=#eb7a23]Weston[/color]-[color= #25b266]Yamada[/color][/bold] representative vomiting their guts out isn’t something that looks good for us, truth be told. Though you can treat yourself once in a while, make sure to keep your drinking in moderation.



  ## Do’s
  This section comprises of tips and tricks of the trade, which can help you on your duties.

  ### Do: Be Creative!
  Although it might make logical sense to try and contact [bold][color=#eb7a23]Weston[/color]-[color= #25b266]Yamada[/color][/bold] HQ for directives, the unfortunate fact of the matter is that fax responses are somewhat uncommon, and objectives even less so. This means that [bold]Corporate Liaison[/bold] is in essence somewhat akin to a choose-your-own adventure role; unlike the Ground Pounders in the Corp, you don’t really have a set objective, meaning that you can do almost anything.

  Of course, there’s some things you probably shouldn’t do (See above), and you should keep in mind that you’re representing [bold][color=#eb7a23]We[/color][color=#25b266]Ya[/color][/bold], thus you’d realistically get in trouble for selling meth to the marines. Furthermore, although you shouldn’t expect a response, it’s always good to forward any signed forms to the Company.

  [bold]Some ideas include:[/bold]
  -Getting the CIC to sign Confidentiality and Asset Protection Agreements
  - Making a deal with the Correspondent(s) to publish or edit their work
  - Speaking with recovered Survivors, getting their stories, and getting NDA’s signed
  - Running PR events
  - Recording damage to the colony
  - Sending reports to WeYa
  - Getting feedback on the performance of Company tech

  And much, much more!
  Truthfully, the sky is the limit for CL. However, coming up with a plan for what to do during a round is only one part of the story. The other, of course, is roleplay.

  ### Do: Stretch Those Social Muscles, Engage with Others!
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookRoleXO"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookRoleCorrespondent"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookRoleSurvivor" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookRoleDoctor" />
  </Box>

  Liaison does actually have one objective presented by the game, and that’s to roleplay with the other players. Although this may initially seem daunting, as most of the marines deploy planetside, and CIC is usually planning and enacting an operation, many other shipside departments, such as the MPs, Engis, Medical, and Requisitions often do have a measure of free time, which makes them key candidates for interactions.

  Furthermore, Correspondents are in the same boat of being mainly roleplay-based, and Survivors can offer fun and interesting roleplay; after all, many of them are [bold][color=#eb7a23]We[/color][color=#25b266]Ya[/color][/bold] employees. Besides just the more work-oriented roleplay, it can always be enjoyable to spend time building rapport and having interpersonal interactions with others, putting aside the Corporate expectations to just have a chat with others.

  ### Do: Use Your Resources
  Due to the importance of your work, you have been supplied with a collection of various items that will help you complete your work. Each one has a specific purpose, and both are very useful.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCPortableVendorCorporate"/>
  </Box>
  The Automated storage briefcase is a briefcase which allows you to purchase a wide collection of items and resources, each one having their own purpose to you (or others). From beer and smokes to communication keys and cash, it holds almost anything an aspiring Liaison needs. However, each item comes with a set “points cost”, which will limit the amount of items you can buy at a time. Don’t worry though: Your vendor's points slowly regenerate back to max.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMFax" Caption="The ever reliable fax machine"/>
  </Box>
  The Hallmark of any self-respecting Corporate Employee. Multipurpose and extremely useful, you’ll find that you can get significant mileage out of a fax machine. These devices are capable of copying inserted pieces of paper, printing out files, and sending messages to any other receiving fax machines. It is also your primary method of contacting [bold][color=#eb7a23]Weston[/color]-[color= #25b266]Yamada[/color][/bold].

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMPaper"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMPaperAlmayerStorage" Caption="A filled-out form"/>
  </Box>
  As the chief bureaucrat aboard the Almayer, you can often get good mileage out of forms and fliers. From getting agreements signed and recorded, to collecting feedback, to collating reports, and even creating and distributing advertisements, paper will become a part of your core gameplay loop. Useful, reliable, and efficient.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMPenClicky"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMPenFountain"/>
  </Box>
  Whoever mocks the phrase [italic]”The pen is mightier than the sword”[/italic] has clearly never been on the receiving end of a particularly nasty lawsuit. Pens are able to write, edit, and sign documents, making them a key part of the Liaison’s toolset. Without it, you wouldn’t be able to make forms.

  ## Conclusion
  [bold]Corporate Liaison[/bold] can initially be an intimidating and confusing role, especially for newer players. However, it can also be fun, engaging, and create one-of-a-kind stories. We hope that this guide has been of help, and we hope to hear good things in the next Company Evaluation.

  Best Regards,

  [italic]The [color=#eb7a23]Weston[/color]-[color= #25b266]Yamada[/color] Corporation[/italic]
  [color=#383838]▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄▄[/color]
  [color=#eb7a23]▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀▀[/color]
</Document>
