<Document>
  #Oppressor, Tier 3
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCXenoOppressor"/>
  ##Playing as a Oppressor
  You are now specialized in being the Queen of Fishing. Firstly let's see what's changed from your Base form. Trade a portion of your speed, a bit of slash damage, slight loss in armor, and acid abilities to become a bulwark of the Queen that gains stun resistance from grenades. Your slashes deal increased damage to prone targets, and you gain a lash that knocks over and flings opponents in front of you as well as a two abilities that can pull in marines.

  Oppressor is unique in its playstyle, specializing in capturing marines from afar and keeping them there for them to be captured by your teammates or by yourself though that doesn't mean its a push over when its comes to damaging marines your dislocation abilities can become very lethal when used in the right way.
  
  ##Abilities:
  - [bold][color=green]PASSIVE[/color][/bold]: Your slashes deal additional damage to prone/knock targets.
  - [bold]Abduct[/bold]: Landing this long ranged ability on:
  - 1 person will drag them in front of you and slow them.
  - 2 people will drag them in front of you, slow them, daze them and briefly root them.
  - 3 or more people will drag them in front of you, slow them and briefly stun them.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookActionXenoAbduct"/>
  - [bold]Dislocate[/bold]: A powerful punch, similar to the warrior's punch. Deals 20 armor piercing damage, 40 if your enemy is slowed. Will also root slowed targets. Reduces other ability cooldowns by 5 seconds.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookActionXenoDislocate"/>
  - [bold]Tail Lash[/bold]: Knock marines back in a 2x3 area in front of you and slow them. Take note that this ability has a wind up.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookActionXenoTailLash"/>
  - [bold]Tail Seize[/bold]: The Oppressor has a unique tail stab, instead called Tail Seize. It has a range of 3 tiles - however, it deals no damage, instead pulling the target in towards you and slowing them for 0.5 seconds upon their arrival.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookActionXenoTailSeize"/>
</Document>
