<Document>
  Guide by Kynthos on Discord

  [color=#5f698a]█    █ █▄ █[/color] [head=2][bold]UNITED NATIONS MARINE CORPS[/bold][/head]\n
  [color=#5f698a]▀ ▄▀ █ ▀█ [/color]

  ##Maintenance Technician

  The Maintenance Technician is a member of the ship's Engineering department. Their primary job is to maintain the integrity of the ship, both the complex engineering tasks of maintaining power, and the menial tasks of keeping the hallways clean. With proper authorization, the Maintenance Technician may be entrusted with various construction projects, on the ship or within the AO. The following tasks are expected from you:

  #Maintaining Power

  Power both on the Almayer and in the AO require generators to be fully functional in order to operate.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGeneratorFusion"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGeneratorFusionColony"/>
  </Box>

  On board the Almayer, power is supplied by the [bold]S-52 Fusion Reactors[/bold]. These start fully operational and powered at the beginning of each operation, and will be completely fine if left unattended.

  In the AO, power is supplied by [bold]G-11 Geothermal Generators[/bold]. These will be depowered and broken when Marines land in the AO, and it will usually be the job of the Combat Technicians to get these repaired. The amount of work required will depend on how damaged the machine is. To repair a generator:

  - First use a [bold]blowtorch[/bold] to weld the panels back together
  - Then use [bold]wire cutters[/bold] to mend the wires.
  - Finally use a [bold]wrench[/bold] to resecure the machine in place.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMWelder"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMWirecutter"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMWrench"/>
  </Box>

  When the blue screen turns on the generator is working and supplying power.

  Power generated by Generators will be wirelessly distributed to APCs. These will store a small amount of power as backup in case the generators fail. Power is then wirelessly distributed to nearby electronics, such as doors, lights, and vendors. If the local APC is destroyed, the immediate area will become depowered. Repairing an APC is as simple as using a screwdriver to fix the panel.

  #Constructing the FOB

  It may be necessary to temporarily send down shipside staff to construct and maintain the Forward Operating Base in the AO. If this happens stay in constant contact with the Chief Engineer who will direct tasks and keep you safe. Dangerous work should be left to the Combat Technicians.

  #Hacking

  In emergencies or when authorized, hacking your way through obstacles to access an inaccessible area may be required. For any hacking job, you will want to be wearing some [bold]insulated gloves[/bold] as well as be equipped with a screwdriver, wire cutters, and security access tuner. To begin hacking:

  - Use a screwdriver to open the maintenance panel.
   <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMScrewdriver"/>
  </Box>
  - Access the machine to open the wire panel.
  - [bold]While wearing insulated gloves[/bold] use a security access tuner or wire cutter to pulse or cut/repair the wires respectively. Each wire will correspond to a function of the machine you are hacking, and interacting with each will disable or alter the way that function works. The wires that controls each function will vary between operations.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMHandsInsulated"/>
  </Box>
  - Once finished, use a screwdriver to close the maintenance panel.

  Most hacking exercises will occur on doors and vending machines. The most common applications are:

  - [Bold]Bolting or Unbolting a Door[/bolt]: Bolting a door is as simple as pulsing or cutting the wire that powers the bolt function. To unbolt a door, you will need to repair the power wires, and then pulse the wire that controls the bolt function. Repairing the wire will not unbolt the door.
  - [bold]Hacking a door open[/bold]: To open a door you do not have access to, cut the two wires that controls the door power. Then use a crowbar to pry the depowered door open. Pulsing one of the power wires will temporarily disable power to the door.
  - [bold]Accessing a locked vending machine[/bold]: To access a vending machine you do not have access to, cut the wire that controls the ID access check, which will allow anyone to dispense items. Pulsing this wire instead will only temporarily disable the ID access check.



  For additional hacking secrets, try asking your fellow Maintenance Technicians or your direct supervisor, the Chief Engineer.

  #Jobs no one else wants to do

  Replacing lights, cleaning up trash, and repairing vandalism are among the many menial tasks you will be entrusted with. It all falls under maintenance. If you've had enough of this, you can always seek authorization for something more creative or explore the halls of the Almayer until an opportunity arises.

  Once you are comfortable with your Engineering skills, try playing [textlink="Combat Technician" link="RMCGuideRoleCombatTechnician"]

  If you are ever unsure of what to do or where to go, seek out the Senior Enlisted Advisor for additional assistance.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookRoleSEA"/>
  </Box>

</Document>
