<Document>

  ##Maintenance Technician

  The Maintenance Technician is a member of the ship’s Engineering department. Their primary job is to maintain the integrity of the ship, both the complex engineering tasks of maintaining power, and the menial tasks of keeping the hallways clean. With proper authorization, the Maintenance Technician may be entrusted with various construction projects, on the ship or within the AO. The following tasks are expected from you:

  #Maintaining Power

  Power both on the Almayer and in the AO requires generators.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGeneratorFusion"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGeneratorFusionColony"/>
  </Box>

  Aboard the Almayer, power is supplied by the [bold]S-52 Fusion Reactors[/bold]. These start fully operational and powered at the beginning of each operation, and will be completely fine if left unattended.

  In the AO, power is supplied by [bold]G-11 Geothermal Generators[/bold]. These will be unpowered and broken when marines land in the AO, and it will usually be the job of the Combat Technicians to get these repaired. The amount of work required will depend on the extent of the damage. To repair a generator:

  - First use a [bold]blowtorch[/bold] to weld the panels back together
  - Then use [bold]wire cutters[/bold] to mend the wires.
  - Finally use a [bold]wrench[/bold] to secure the machine in place.

  When the blue screen turns on the generator is working and supplying power.

  Power generated will be automatically distributed to APCs, which will store a small amount of power within its installed power cell in case the generators fail. Power is then distributed to nearby electronics in the area, such as doors, lights, and vendors. The total power draw will be listed on the APC’s interface. If the local APC is destroyed, or its power cell depleted, the immediate area will become unpowered.

    To replace the power cell of an APC, first swipe your Engineering ID card or Dogtags to unlock the interface and disengage the cover lock. Then use a crowbar to force the cover open, allowing access to the power cell, which can be removed with an empty hand and replaced with a charged power cell. Once swapped, use a crowbar to close the panel, engage the cover lock, and swipe your ID to lock the APC interface again. This can be used to temporarily keep a small area powered in case despite the lack of power generation.

    If the APC is destroyed, it can be reassembled by using a screwdriver.

    #Reloading the Orbital Cannon

    The bow of the Almayer houses the devastating Orbital Cannon, used to rain hellfire upon the enemies of the UNMC. Maintenance Technicians are directly responsible for maintaining this on behalf of the CIC, which is accessible via the nearby Maintenance tunnels. This should be only conducted under direct orders from the Commander of the operation to ensure the correct bomb is chambered.

    The Almayer will start with random warheads found nearby the Cannon, as well as plenty of solid fuel tanks to power the machine. Command will have the means to obtain more warheads should they be required.

    There are several bombs you may be asked to load, and you can confirm the payload type by inspecting it.

    Once the payload type is confirmed with the Commander, use the Orbital Cannon Console to determine how much fuel launching the payload will take. This will be different between operations.

    Using a Power Loader, carry the Warhead and the correct number of Solid fuel tanks and insert them into the Orbital Cannon itself. The Cannon Console will display what has been loaded in case you forget. Once the Cannon is loaded, use the Console to load the payload, and then chamber the payload.

    [bold]While a loaded payload can be unloaded, once a payload is chambered it can only be unloaded by firing the cannon![/bold]

    Upon completion, notify your superiors, as only they are authorized to fire such a brutal weapon. Until the Cannon needs to be reloaded, your job here is complete.

  #Constructing the FOB

  It may be necessary to temporarily send down shipside staff to construct and maintain the Forward Operating Base in the AO. If this happens stay in constant contact with the Chief Engineer who will direct tasks and keep you safe. Dangerous work should be left to the Combat Technicians.

  #Hacking

  In emergencies or when authorized, hacking your way through obstacles to access an inaccessible area may be required. For any hacking job, you will want to be wearing some [bold]insulated gloves[/bold] as well as be equipped with a screwdriver, wire cutters, and security access tuner. To begin hacking:

  - Use a screwdriver to open the maintenance panel.
  - Access the machine to open the wire panel.
  - [bold]While wearing insulated gloves[/bold] use a security access tuner or wire cutter to pulse or cut/repair the wires respectively. Each wire will correspond to a function of the machine you are hacking and interacting with each will disable or alter the way that function works. The wires that control each function will vary between operations.
  - Once finished, use a screwdriver to close the maintenance panel.

  Most hacking exercises will occur on doors and vending machines. The most common applications are:

  - [Bold]Bolting or Unbolting a Door[/bolt]: Bolting a door is as simple as pulsing or cutting the wire that powers the bolt function. To unbolt a door, you will need to repair the power wires, and then pulse the wire that controls the bolt function. Repairing the wire will not unbolt the door.
  - [bold]Hacking a door open[/bold]: To open a door you do not have access to, cut the two wires that controls the door power. Then use a crowbar to pry the depowered door open. Pulsing one of the power wires will temporarily disable power to the door.
  - [bold]Accessing a locked vending machine[/bold]: To access a vending machine you do not have access to, cut the wire that controls the ID access check, which will allow anyone to dispense items. Pulsing this wire instead will only temporarily disable the ID access check.



  For additional hacking secrets, try asking your fellow Maintenance Technicians or your direct supervisor, the Chief Engineer.

  #Jobs no one else wants to do

  Replacing lights, cleaning up trash, and repairing vandalism are among the many menial tasks you will be entrusted with. It all falls under maintenance after all. If you’ve had enough of this, you can always seek authorization for something more creative or explore the halls of the Almayer until an opportunity arises.

  Once you are comfortable with your Engineering skills, try enlisting as a [textlink="Combat Technician" link="RMCGuideRoleCombatTechnician"].

  If you are ever unsure of what to do or where to go, seek out the Senior Enlisted Advisor for additional assistance.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookRoleSEA"/>
  </Box>

</Document>
