<Document>
  #Boiler, Tier 3
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMXenoBoiler"/>
  ##Playing as a Boiler
  Become the ultimate ranged warrior of the Hive with your signature bombard capable of stalling any hosts. It is now slow, large and returns to being a supportive role on the frontline, attaining an upgraded acid spray, corrosive acid and tail stab toxin.

  Make sure to always stay behind other sisters as you are weak alone. Always melt green flares so that you do not get killed instantly by skyspit (close air support) fire.

  Its [color=green]acidic[/color] globs are capable of killing off any hosts caught within, while its [color=yellow]neurotoxin[/color] variant spreads further and will weaken any hosts allowing for capture.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookXenoBombardAcidProjectile"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookXenoBombardNeurotoxinProjectile"/>
  </Box>\n

  Remember to melt green flares and stay away from red dots as they pose a great threat to you from above.

  Due to high acid reserves, the Boiler glows in the dark making it seen by any host easily, this also makes the Boiler incredibly vulnerable to [color=red]fire[/color].
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCTileFire"/>
  ##Door tech
  To safely use bombard you can stand behind a closed resin door and charge your bombard. Make sure to aim outside the path of the door, then hover your mouse over the door and press [color=yellow][bold][keybind="ActivateItemInWorld"][/bold][/color] when the bombard is almost done, if timed then the resin door will open letting your glob pass through!
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DoorXenoResin"/>
  ##Abilities:
  - [bold][color=#E61919]PASSIVE[/color][/bold]: Vulnerable to fire and glows in the dark.
  - [bold]Strong Corrosive Acid[/bold]: Secretes a glob of acid on items to be dissolved.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoCorrosiveAcid"/>
  - [bold]Toggle Long Range Sight[/bold]: Look further in the direction you are facing.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoToggleLongRangeSight"/>
  - [bold]Bombard[/bold]: Prepare to fire, either an acidic or neurotoxic glob. This will go past your aimed position if it does not hit anything.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoBombard"/>
  - [bold]Toggle Gas Type[/bold]: Toggles between Acid Or Neurotoxin.
  - Acid: Will burn targets and barricades.
  - Neurotoxin: Cripples and weakens targets, has a larger cloud range.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoToggleGasType"/>
  - [bold]Spray Acid[/bold]: Sprays acid along the ground in a line, covering any barricades and stunning hosts caught in its path.
  - Will also extinguish any sisters if they are on fire.
  - If used on a host affected by Charged Spit from a spitter, will upgrade the spit and stun them.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoSprayAcid"/>
  - [bold]Acid Shroud[/bold]: Create a cloud of acid around you, disabling your other abilities. Used in last resort.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookActionXenoAcidShroud"/>
</Document>
