<Document>
  # Intel

  <Box>
    "The six categories of intelligence operations are: planning and direction; collection; processing and exploitation; analysis and production; dissemination and integration; and evaluation and feedback."
    \n- U.S. mil, JP 2-0
  </Box>

  ## Sources

  - Intelligence can be gathered by anyone, though some sources require specialized training.

  [color=#A88B5E][bold]Uplink[/bold][/color]

  - Restoring [textlink="power" link="RMCGuideRoleCombatTechnician"] and [textlink="communications" link="RMCGuideCommunicationsTowers"] for the first time grants intel points.

  [color=#A88B5E][bold]Bodies[/bold][/color]

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookRoleSurvivor" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookCorpseColonistBurst" />
  </Box>

  - Survivors award points the first time they arrive on the warship.
  - Dead colonists must be stored in the morgue.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMXenoDefender" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMXenoWarrior" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCXenoCrusher" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMXenoQueen" />
  </Box>

  - Xenonidss must be stored in the research containment room on the second floor of medical.
  \n\t- The bigger they are, the more points they award.
  \n\t- Note that immature ones (Parasites, Larvas and Lesser Drones) do not award any points.

  [color=#A88B5E][bold]Documents and devices[/bold][/color]

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCIntelPaperScrap" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCIntelProgressReport" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCIntelFolder" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCIntelTechnicalManual" />
  </Box>

  1. These documents must be read by trained personnel.
  \n\t\t\t- More complex documents require that you have read easier ones before.
  \n\t\t\t- scrap -> report -> folder -> manual
  \n2. The gained knowledge must then be entered into the intel computer found in the intel room.
  \n3. The read document must then be stored in the intel room.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCIntelRetrieveHealthAnalyzer" />
  </Box>

  - These devices must be stored in the intel room.

  ## Working in intelligence

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookRoleASO" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCGuidebookRoleIO" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookRoleYou" />
  </Box>

  You have chosen, or been chosen, to work in intelligence.
  Your primary role will be to collect and process intel from the sources mentioned above.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCPouchDocument" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCIntelDetector" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCFulton" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMEncryptionKeyIntel" />
  </Box>

  To aid you in this you have been supplied with the tools listed above.\nNote that [textlink="requisitions" link="RMCRequisitions"] also has these in stock.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCVisorNightVision" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCKitIntel" />
  </Box>

  There are however two "unique" things that requisitions can't help you with.
  One is the rechargeable night vision optic that allow you to see in the dark for a limited amount of time.
  The other is the field intelligence support kit that includes the tools listed above plus an intelligence pamphlet that teaches the reader how to use the intel computer.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCComputerIntel" />
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCTechTreeConsole" />
  </Box>

  After getting geared up you should make yourself familiar with the devices in the intel room and CIC.
  The intel computer is used to write down what you have read in documents and the tech tree console allows you to spend your collected intelligence.

  [color=#A88B5E][bold]Deployment[/bold][/color]

  Or rather: "[italic]Thanks for all that but how will it actually go down?[/italic]"

  - The ASO will sit in the intel lab to read and sort all incoming documents, and submit the gained knowledge into the intel computer.
  - The CMO will drag dead xenonids into the research lab.
  - The Pilots and DCCs will install a fulton recovery system, normally on the Normandy, but sometimes also on the Alamo.
  - The IOs will form a squad, sometimes including a couple other marines, to gather intelligence.
  - Marines that took fultons with them should extract dead xenonids.
  - Marines that picked up intel should pass it to passing IOs, the FOB or fulton it out in crates.

  Talk to your superior or SEA if you are confused or have any questions.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookRoleSEA"/>
  </Box>
</Document>
