<Document>

  #Medical

  ##CPR
  - Remove their mask.
  - Click on a patient to attempt CPR.
  - Doing this once every 7 seconds will lower their oxygen damage.
  - This will also slightly extend the period of which bodies can be revived each time.

  ##Treating {wounds}
  - When a marine takes damage, they will recieve treatable wounds.
  - Untreated wounds are indicated by [bold]"{  }"[/bold] around their damage numbers.
  - When wounds are treated, the marine will begin to passively heal, very slowly.
  - Treating wounds will also stop any bleeding.
  - Using medicine will speed up damage healing.
  - [textlink="Medicines" link="RMCMedicine"]

  ##Items that treat {wounds}
  - Trauma and burn kits will treat all wounds when used, and provide minor bonus healing.
  - Surgical line and synth graft will treat some wounds each time used, with some healing each use.
  - Gauze and ointment will treat all wounds when used, but only ointment provides minor bonus healing.
  - Surgical line and synth graft can still be used after applying a trauma or burn kit.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMTraumaKit10"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMBurnKit10"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMSurgicalLine"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMSynthGraft"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGauze10"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMOintment10"/>
  </Box>\n

  ##Blood and bloodloss
  - When a marine has a low blood level, they will begin to take oxygen damage.
  - To replenish blood, use blood packs.
  - They can be inserted into a patient by hand, or injected by an IV.
  - To use a blood pack in hand, click it on the patient.
  - Click the patient again to remove the injector.
  - To use an IV, insert the bag, then drag the IV sprite over the patient.
  - Click the IV to remove the IV from the patient.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMBloodPackFull"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMIV"/>
  </Box>\n

  ##Defibs
  - Defibs can be used to revive a marine below 200 damage.
  - Epinephrine can be used to heal a marine when they are defibbed.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMDefibrillator"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMEpinephrineAutoInjector"/>
  </Box>\n

  ##Surgery
  - To begin surgery, use a surgical tool on the patient.
  - Select a body part to work on, then follow the steps of your chosen surgery.
  - For larva removal, ensure you are a trained doctor and not a nurse or corpsman.
  - Place the patient on an operating table, then begin the operation.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMCrateSecureSurgery"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMScalpel"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMOperatingTable"/>
  </Box>\n

</Document>
