<Document>
#Survivor

[color=red]bold[Survivor is an extremely difficult role that assumes you are familiar with the basics of the game.[/bold][/color]

You are a Survivor of whatever fate befell your facility. You either worked, or lived here, and managed to evade danger… until now! You are completely aware of the threat and may use whatever knowledge you have to stay alive, [bold]but help may not come[/bold]. The only people you can rely on are yourself and your fellow Survivors, if any lived to tell their tales.

From the second you’re able to you must be working towards improving your survival chances. Every moment that passes is a moment closer towards a gruesome death. You’re going to need ways to defend yourself.

First grab your radio from your survival pouch and talk into it to establish contact with other survivors. The more people you are with, the more likely survival becomes. Organise a place to meet or arrange for small groups to fan out and collect supplies.

Local security outposts may have an armoury to raid for armour and weapons. Engineering facilities will supply tools and building materials. The medical centres will house medical supplies. Along your travels you may find the bodies of those who did not survive... maybe they found something you could use?

Once you’re supplied you should find a place to fortify. Ideal locations are away from high traffic areas and contain an escape route that you can use should your fortifications fall. Having another safe area to run to can be the difference between life and death, so don’t put all your eggs in one basket.

Alternatively, instead of actively fighting back you can attempt to evade the threat altogether. Hiding spots such as crates and lockers can mask your location and make you extremely difficult to find. However, if you are found...

Remember, Survivor is an open-ended role with limitless possibilities. There is no wrong way to try and stay alive, and while this feat is almost impossible, the keyword is [bold]almost[/bold].

</Document>
