<Document>

  #So, you've ascended to the throne of the Hive!
  #Now what?

  - Rejoice! You are the Queen, the beating heart of the Xenomorph swarm. Your will shapes the Hive, and your command directs its wrath.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMXenoQueen"/>
  </Box>\n
  - As the matriarch, your duty is to expand, defend, and lead. Without you, the Hive crumbles—but with you, it thrives.
  - For intermediate players wishing to try out the commanding side of Xenos, this will start with what should be done at the start.

  #Now what?
  First we must choose our hive location, this is not that all important and selecting where you spawn as your hive location will do. Once you have found a hive location follow the steps.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookActionXenoOrderConstruction"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="HiveCoreXeno"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookActionXenoPheromones"/>
  </Box>\n
   
  - Use your Order Construction ability to create a hive core and then fill it with your plasma.
  - You can emit recovery pheremones to gain plasma to fill the hivecore, remember your pheromones are the strongest in the hive! 

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoHiveWeeds"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookActionXenoGrowOvipositor"/>
  </Box>\n
  
  - Once filled, move ontop of the new hive weeds emitted from the hivecore then grow your ovipositor.
  - Remember to stand still whhile growing your ovipositor.
  
  Well done, you have successfully grown your ovipositor to allow for your children to gain evolution and thrive, 

  - Another important job of the Drone is to plant weeds.
  - Weeds allow us to rest to regain our health and energy!
  - We can also only construct the hive on weeds.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookActionXenoRest"/>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoWeeds"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoWeedsSource"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoWeeds"/>
  </Box>\n

  - Our final goal is to protect the Queen and plant her eggs so our hive may grow!
  - Eggs can be placed on weeds, and contain parasites.
  - Parasites can be extracted from the eggs, but be wary that parasites have short lifespans away from the weeds!

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMXenoQueen"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoEgg"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="XenoWeeds"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMXenoParasite"/>
  </Box>\n

  - When a parasite is placed on a living host, a new larva will be born! Rejoice!
  - Hosts that hold the growing larva are very precious, and should be secured to a resin wall as soon as possible.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SalvageHumanCorpse"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMXenoLarva"/>
  </Box>\n

</Document>
