<Document>
[color=#5f698a]█    █ █▄ █[/color] [head=2][bold]UNITED NATIONS MARINE CORPS[/bold][/head]\n
[color=#5f698a]▀ ▄▀ █ ▀█ [/color]

#UNMC Rifleman's Primer
  - Rise and shine, soldier! Get up and get tactical!

  - You've just woken up, so you're hungry. Head to the food vendor, dispense two meals from the machine and get them down your neck. If you have complaints about the food, you can address them to someone who gives a damn!
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ColMarTechFood"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMMarinePreparedMealChicken"/>
  </Box>
   - You can't bring those trays with you, so leave them on a nearby table or throw them into the disposals. God help you if I catch you throwing them anywhere else!
  <Box>
  [color=red]MARINE! You cannot fight in your shorts! Get dressed! DOUBLE TIME! [/color]
  </Box>
  - Haul your ass to the automated equipment vendor and get your uniform on. Click on the vending machine, and then click the "Standard Marine Apparel".
  - This will give you your uniform, including undersuit, boots, gloves, helmet, and headset - and you will wear them at ALL TIMES.
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ColMarTechEquipment"/>

  - Take note of the colors on your helmet, they denote your squad:\n
  [color=#E61919]Red for Alpha[/color], [color=#FFC32D]Yellow for Bravo[/color], [color=#C864C8]Purple for Charlie[/color], and [color=#4148C8]Blue for Delta[/color].

  - You now have your choice of equipment. You will only be dispensed one item per category (two for pouches) so choose carefully. Anything marked in [color=green]Green[/color] is recommended for your role, so grab yourself some light or medium armor, an M276 Ammo Load Rig, some first aid pouches, and a gas mask or coif if you so desire.
    <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMBeltMarine"/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCPouchFirstAid"/>
    </Box>
  - You have 45 points to spend on extra equipment, such as grenades, tools, or special ammo! Each item has its own point cost and some items are better value than others. For now, grab some extended or armor-piercing magazines for the M54C and store them in your belt.

  <Box>[color=red]Now you look like a marine![/color]
  </Box>
  - Now you're ready for prom but you ain't leaving this house without a chaperone!
  - Head to the Automated Weapon rack and select your weapon. As before, recommended items are colored [color=green]Green[/color].
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ColMarTechGuns"/>
  </Box>
   - Meet your new best friend, the [bold]M54C Assault Rifle MK2[/bold]. Take some extra magazines and put them in your belt or pouches, and don't forget to load the gun.
   - Now you might be tempted to take your new buddy for a spin and get to know eachother a little better. Head to the firing range if you want to practice your aim.
   -If you are not in the firing range you [color=red]do not[/color] discharge your weapon!
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="RMCWeaponRifleM54C"/>
   - Make sure you have some standard and armor-piercing (AP) magazines. AP will punch through tougher targets, and that includes marines so WATCH. YOUR. FIRE.
  <Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMMagazineRifleM54C"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMMagazineRifleM54CAP"/>
  </Box>
  - Inside the armory you will also find machines dispensing surplus uniforms, tools, munitions, and weapon attachments. We will cover weapon attachments in more detail another time.
  <Box>[color=red]You're mean, you're green, you're a UN Marine! OORAH![/color]
  </Box>

  - Find your squadmates and head to briefing. If you're late to the party, head straight west to the hangar bay and get ready for deployment.

  - If you need any help, you can ask any of your fellow marines, or your local mentor, the Senior Enlisted Advisor.
  - If you need extra assistance or have a problem, you can press F1 to contact a mentor.
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CMGuidebookRoleSEA"/>
  </Box>
<Box>[color=red]SEMPER FI, MARINE! DISMISSED![/color]
</Box>
</Document>
