<Document>
  # General roleplay standards


  ## Character memory
  - Your personal character may remember events that occured in previous missions and discuss them, but may not mention their own death or the death of another present character.

  ## Use realistic character names, avoid names of known people and characters
  Pick a realistic name that could appear on a birth certificate with at least a first and last name (leeway is given to for non-human races).
  - No names of people or characters from the real world
  - No titles/honorifics. Titles and honorifics include but are not limited to; Dr/Doctor, Jr/Junior, Major.
  - Names must follow all other rules (no slurs/sexual names/etc)
  - Usernames, objects, random characters, very "low effort" names, "meta" names, or otherwise implausible names cannot be used as names.
  - Admin rulings on IC names are final and disputes should be done through the forums, not by refusing to comply with an admin
  - Nicknames, within reason, may be applied to humanoid character's names, in the format of "Firstname 'Nickname' Lastname". Nicknames can be at most two words.
  - Up to two characters of Roman numerals may be used.

  ## Act like an actual character in this setting.
  - Do not use text speak or emoticons in character, and do not refer to out of character things like admins or rounds in-game.
  - Do not threaten players that you are calling the admins on them.
  - Do not use emotes to bypass speech filters or muteness.
  - You are not required to write a backstory; however, you are expected to at least make an effort to act like your role.

  ## Suicides
  - You must have a valid roleplay reason to commit suicide.
  - Starting and then cancelling a suicide will be treated the same as an actual suicide, and also requires a valid reason.
  - Suiciding at round-end without a valid roleplay reason will be considered end-of-round grief and result in the same ban.

  Valid suicide examples:
  - Suiciding as a survivor in a last stand scenario, when it is clear that you will be captured by xenonids and there is no hope of fighting back.
  - Suiciding to avoid being captured by a hostile force.
  - Suiciding if you fail to evac in a post-hijack evacuation of the Almayer.

  Not valid suicide examples:
  - Suiciding at round end without a valid roleplay reason. Going out after a victory is not a valid reason.
  - Suiciding in briefing.
  - Suiciding to spite someone or because you want to stop playing the round.
  - Suiciding after receiving bad orders.
  - Suiciding at round-start because you didn't get the role you wanted.
  - Suiciding at memorial in remembrance of fallen marines.
  - Suiciding because you are wounded.

  If you are not sure if you have a valid reason, AHelp (F1) to ask.

</Document>
