<Document>
  # General roleplay standards


  ## Character memory
  - Your personal character may remember events that occured in previous missions and discuss them, but may not mention their own death or the death of another present character.

  ## Use realistic character names, avoid names of known people and characters
  Pick a realistic name that could appear on a birth certificate with at least a first and last name (leeway is given to for non-human races).
  - Any species may use the "human name format" (Firstname Lastname). Characters sharing naming formats with another species otherwise should have an in-character lore reasoning.
  - No names of people or characters from the real world
  - No titles/honorifics. Titles and honorifics include but are not limited to; Dr/Doctor, Jr/Junior, Major.
  - Names must follow all other rules (no slurs/sexual names/etc)
  - Usernames, objects, random characters, very "low effort" names, "meta" names, or otherwise implausible names cannot be used as names.
  - Admin rulings on IC names are final and disputes should be done through the forums, not by refusing to comply with an admin
  - Up to two characters of Roman numerals may be used.

  ## Nicknames
  - Nicknames, within reason, may only be applied to "human name format". [italic]Any species may use the "human name format" (Firstname Lastname)[/italic]
  - They may be used in the format of, in single quotes, [bold]"Firstname 'Nickname' Lastname"[/bold].
  - Nicknames can be at most two words.

  ## Artificial Womb Soldiers
  [italics]This soldiers do not have any biological parents who have passed along their last name to them. Instead these soldiers have been assigned a regular first name, the AW initials as a middle name and a weapon as their surname.[/italics]
  - May only be applied to "human name format".
  - As an AW Soldier you MUST have a weapon as your last name.
  - This weapon needs to have been used/developed before or during 1975 or earlier. (Vulcan, Sword, etc.)
  - For example; James AW Sword

  ## Act like an actual character in this setting.
  - Do not use text speak or emoticons in character, and do not refer to out of character things like admins or rounds in-game.
  - Do not threaten players that you are calling the admins on them.
  - Do not use emotes to bypass speech filters or muteness.
  - You are not required to write a backstory; however, you are expected to at least make an effort to act like your role.

</Document>
