<Document>

  # Character Names

  [italic]Admin rulings on IC names are final and disputes should be done through appeals, not by refusing to comply.[/italic]

  ## General Restrictions
  [italic]Non-human characters have leeway with their own naming formats, listed in character naming formats.\n\nGenerally speaking, you can use up to one choice of uniqueness to your name, such as a choice between either a nickname, or a species-specific format.[/italic]
  - The goal of your character name should not be to be "funny".
  - Pick a realistic name that could appear on a birth certificate with a first and last name, or based on your chosen character species.
  - No names or references of people or characters from the real world.
  - No titles/honorifics.\nTitles and honorifics include but are not limited to; Dr/Doctor, Jr/Junior, Major.
  - Names must follow all other rules (no slurs/sexual names/etc)
  - Usernames, objects, random characters, "low effort", "meta/ooc", or otherwise implausible names cannot be used as names. (Fights-the-Xenonids is not valid)
  - Up to two characters of Roman numerals may be used.

  ## Nicknames

  ### What is a Nickname?
  - Nicknames are something your character is called by others, not an adjective or extension of your name.
  - Try making a callsign, or an ironic nickname such as 'Quickdraw' for someone who fumbles their weapons often.

  ### Restrictions
  - Nicknames may only be applied to human name format. Read Character Naming Formats.
  - They may be used in 'single' quotes,\n[bold]Firstname 'Nickname' Lastname[/bold]. (not "double" quotes)
  - Nicknames can be at most two words.

  ## Character Naming Formats
  [italic]Any character may use the human (standard) name format. Characters sharing naming formats with another species otherwise should have an in-character lore reasoning, such as being adopted. For species not requiring a last name, the first name should be exotic to warrant such. Information about each species can be found on the wiki.[/italic]
  - Humans, Felinids, Vulpkanin: The standard naming format.\n[bold]Firstname Lastname[/bold] "John Smith"
  - Dwarves: Similar to the human name format, with a viking theme. Try using the randomizer.\n[bold]Firstname Lastname[/bold] "Erik Lightningclaw"
  - Reptilians, Lizards: Exotic names, try using the randomizer. A last name is optional.\n[bold]Name1-Name2[/bold] "Beewos-Azala"
  - Reptilians, Lizards: (Second format) usually a nickname related to the character's interests.\n[bold]Verb-article-noun[/bold] "Fights-The-Wars"
  - Diona: Nature themed.\n[bold]Noun of Noun[/bold]"The Flower of Union"
  - Moth: Latin or light themed names. A last name is optional.\n[bold]Firstname Lastname[/bold]"Lucy Emperor"
  - Arachnids: Latin themed names. A last name is optional.\n[bold]Firstname Lastname[/bold]"Spiroctenus Triangularis"
  - Avali: Exotic single names and can include a last name with a dash. Try the randomizer. \n[bold]Firstname-Lastname[/bold] "Ralomi" "Ralomi-Jasyo"
  - Rodentia: Simple names that consist of an adjective, and a single name. The adjective is optional.\n[bold]Adjective Firstname[/bold] "Shifty Fin"
  - Slime-People: Standard naming format. A last name is optional.\n[bold]Firstname Lastname[/bold] "John Smith"
  - Skrell: Exotic names, a last name is optional. Try the randomizer.\n[bold]Firstname Lastname[/bold] "Teqtaq Xuexum"
  - Feroxi: Standard naming format, with some exotic flavor.\n[bold]Firstname Lastname[/bold] "Ralvox Alunethis"

  ## Artificial Womb Soldiers
  [italic]These soldiers do not have any biological parents who have passed along their last name to them. Instead, these soldiers have been assigned a regular first name, the AW initials as a middle name and a weapon as their surname. More information about these soldiers can be found on the RMC Wiki.[/italic]
  - May only be applied to human name format. Any character may use the human name format.
  - As an AW Soldier you have a weapon as your last name. This weapon needs to have been used/developed before or during 1975 or earlier. (Vulcan, Sword, etc.)\n\nFor example; James AW Sword


</Document>
