<Document>
  # General roleplay standards


  ## Character memory
  - Characters may remember events that occured in previous operations and discuss them, but may not mention their own death or the death of another present character.
  - Faction specific knowledge varies and can be found on their individual pages.

  ## Act Like a Character in this Setting.
  [bold]The local out of character channel is exempt from any roleplay requirements.[/bold] Out of character jokes and similar can be used in this channel with no issues.
  - Characters are not required to have a backstory; however, you are expected to at least make an effort to act like your role and still be a background character within the setting if choosing not to interact with others.
  - Some actions have no delay to make gameplay smoother, like reloading. Do not abuse instances of this to spam any kind of sounds.
  - Use acceptable character names outlined in the rules.

  ### Do not
  - Use internet or meme-based language, text shortcuts like "pls", or emoticons in character.
  - Refer to out of character concepts, such as "admins", "cooldowns", etc in character.
  - Reference memes, internet culture, phrases, etc in character.
  - Use emotes or the local out of character channel to bypass speech filters or muteness.\nOnly mechanical sign language is permitted, which is not available at this time.

  ## Suicides
  - You must have a valid roleplay based reason to commit suicide. There are no OOC reasons.\n[bold]If you are not sure if you have a valid reason, AHelp (F1) to ask.[/bold]
  - Cancelling a suicide will be treated the same, and also requires a valid reason.

  ### Valid suicide reasons:
  - A last stand scenario, when it is clear that you will be captured by xenonids and there is no hope of fighting back.
  - To avoid being captured by a hostile force that will probably torture you.
  - If you fail to evacuate in a post-hijack evacuation of the Almayer, or if your evacuation method crashes.
  - Late stage parasite infection.

  ### Invalid suicide Reasons:
  - The round has ended, or is near ending.\nThis will be considered end of round grief.
  - To spite someone.
  - To stop playing the round.
  - After receiving bad orders.
  - At round-start when you don't get the role you wanted.
  - At memorial or after successful warship evacuation due to marine losses.
  - Because you are wounded but recoverable.

  ## Metagaming/Powergaming

  [bold]Some parts of the game cannot be covered by mechanics to ensure proper roleplay and balance:[/bold]

  Other cases are listed per faction in their respective pages.

  - Exploitation of any current game bugs, for an advantage or to be "funny". You can ask in ahelp if something is a bug to avoid this.

  ### Objective Defenses

  - All non-xenonid roles may not encase objectives in walls.
  - Objective defenses must have at least one tile of entrance that can be blocked with barricades.\n\nExamples of objectives include but are not limited to sensors, communications, APCs, nuke.

</Document>
