<Document>
  # Marine roleplay standards

  Rules regarding crimes in character can be found in the [textlink="core rules" link="RMCKindness"].

  ## General Knowledge
  - The Marines have understanding of all possible threats, including details of all xenonids.
  - The marines are not aware nor believe in the capability of the xenonids to interact with dropships, and may only act in response to the actual "hijack likely" announcement by the warship's systems.
  - All personnel employed by the Marines are mentally stable and fit for duty.\nThey would not be placed in this position or allowed to enlist otherwise.
  - Don't openly try to cooperate with obvious or known hostile forces as a member of the opposite faction.
  - Don't use information you gain from outside your own character's view and hearing to your advantage. You remember all events up until you fall unconscious.\nCharacters are not unconscious during being infected alone, just blinded and muted. This shown by the game mechanics.

  ## Start of Round
  - The Marines are not yet aware there are xenonids on the planet at the start of the operation.
  - Marines are to assist [bold]survivors[/bold] by saving them from the planet. Do not antagonize them.
  - Don't disrupt the start of the round (first drop).\nIf you're engaging in unrelated or disruptive activities (including but not limited to; fights, minor crime, tackling others), keep it to the lower deck gym, where the boxing ring is located.

  # Follow Role Objectives
  - Important non-rifleman roles such corpsmen should be following their role objectives.\nFor corpsmen, this would mean healing others.
  - Most if not all jobs that are not "marine jobs", such as nurses and maintenance technicians, are not combat roles.\nFeel free to ask if you have any questions about where a role works.
  - All "marine jobs" should deploy when possible.
  - Correspondents focus on reporting on combat and disengage when attacked.
  - Liaisons are not antagonists to the marines, command, or the operation.

  ## Character Restrictions: Synthetics/etc
  - Characters, in any role, that are not synthetics by role must be entirely biological, and genuinely sentient; capable of independent thought, emotions, and free will.
  - Artificial intelligence, programmed personalities, or synthetic minds are not permitted outside of this role.

  ## Warship modifications
  - Deconstruction of the warship for materials should not be occuring early into the round. Do not immediately resort to taking the warship to pieces for a random unconfirmed distress call.
  \n\nThis includes salvaging of things like chairs in briefing, however does not include the barrels and crates in maintenance.
  - Modifications to the warship should not be made with meta-purposes, do not build a maze or bunker on the warship intended to secure the warship for hijack before "hijack likely" is announced by the warship systems.

</Document>
