<Document>
  # Marine roleplay standards

  Rules regarding crimes in character can be found in the [textlink="core rules" link="RMCKindness"].

  ## General Knowledge
  - The Marines have knowledge of all possible threats.
  - The marines are not aware nor believe in the capability of the xenonids to interact with dropships, and may only act in response to the actual hijack announcement.
  - All personnel employed by the Marines are mentally stable and fit for duty.
  - Don't openly try to cooperate with obvious or known hostile forces as a member of the opposite faction.

  ## Start of Round
  - The Marines are not yet aware there are xenonids on the planet at the start of the operation.
  - Marines are to assist [bold]survivors[/bold] by saving them from the planet. Do not antagonize them.
  - Do not disrupt the start of the round (first drop). If you're engaging in unrelated or disruptive activities (including but not limited to; fights, minor crime, tackling others), keep it to the lower deck gym, where the boxing ring is located.

  # Follow Role Objectives
  - Important marines such as specialists and smart gun operators and corpsmen should be following their role objectives.
  - All combat roles should deploy when possible.
  - Medical roles (excluding corpsmen) are not combat roles.

  ## Correspondents
  - Correspondents focus on reporting on combat and disengage when attacked.

  ## Character Restrictions - Synthetics/Similar
  - Characters that are not synthetics by role must be entirely biological, and genuinely sentient; capable of independent thought, emotions, and free will.
  - Artificial intelligence, programmed personalities, or synthetic minds are not permitted outside of this role.

  ## Ship modifications
  - Deconstruction of the ship for materials should not be occuring before first drop. The marines would not immediately resort to taking their warship to pieces for a random unconfirmed distress call.
  - Includes salvaging of things like chairs in briefing, however does not include the barrels and crates in maintenance.
  - Includes the removal of supplies from the ship where not explicitly necessary. You would not drag half the contents of the medical bay to the field immediately.
  - Modifications to the ship should not be made with meta-purposes, do not build a maze or bunker on the ship intended to secure the ship for hijack before you even know hijack is a thing.

</Document>
