<Document>
  # Survivor Roleplay Standards

  ## General
  - Survivors must accept requests/invitations to board the Almayer for the first time, but are not required to stay after they arrive. Make sure to follow the direction and requests of the Military Police, if you are not immediately redeploying.

  ## All forms of hostility to Marines is not permitted
  - Survivors have more leeway than marines with mental stability due to trauma experienced during the xenonid attack. They may be suffering PTSD, paranoia or similar conditions for roleplaying purposes.
  - Despite this, all survivors should not become hostile or cause drastic issues for the marines in any way, such as stealing their secure equipment, starting fights, or preventing them from accessing any part of the AO.

  [bold]Exceptions[/bold]
  - If there is an exception in hostility due to faction it will be clear and written to the player. Do not assume that a survivor role is hostile for any other reason.
  - Hostile Faction Survivors cannot attempt to harm other survivors.

  ## Survivors VS Xenonids
  - Survivors should not engage or seek any xenonids before the roundstart xenos have had a chance to evolve (5 minutes). If a xenonid enters your vision, but you were not seeking them, you are free to attack them as they have forfeited their early round protection.

  ## Metagaming/Powergaming

  - Surrounding an objective structure such as towers or APCs entirely with reinforced walls to prevent Xenonids attacking it [bold]without T3s[/bold] is not allowed. This is usually only relevant in the early game.\nWalls can be used to cover most of the object, however there must remain access for other xenos IE barricades.\nThis rule is no longer applied as soon as a T3 Xenonid has been witnessed.
  - Do not hunt, move, or secure or otherwise interact with monkeys to deny Xenonid captures. These monkeys lessen the amount of xenos at the start of the round, and make your life easier.

  [bold]Intel Objectives[/bold]

  - Survivors may not attempt to secure intel unless they are assisted or have been enlisted into the marines.
  - Survivors may pull and gather corpses of dead humanoids and xenonid corpses provided they are acting and speaking in character and not acting and speaking as if to secure intel.

</Document>
