<Document>
  # Survivor Roleplay Standards

  ## General
  - Survivors must accept requests/invitations to board the Almayer for the first time, but are not required to stay after they arrive. Make sure to follow the direction and requests of the Military Police.

  ## Hostility to Marines is Not Permitted
  - Survivors have more leeway than marines with mental stability due to trauma experienced during the xenonid attack.\nThey may be suffering PTSD, paranoia or similar conditions for roleplaying purposes.\n\nDespite this, all survivors may not become hostile or cause drastic issues for the marines in any way, such as stealing their secure equipment, starting verbal or physical fights, or preventing them from accessing any part of the operation.

  [bold]Exceptions[/bold]
  - If there is an exception in hostility due to faction it will be clear and written to the player. Do not assume that a survivor role is hostile for any other reason.
  - Hostile Faction Survivors cannot attempt to harm other survivors.

  ## Survivors VS Xenonids

  Not all maps and spawn locations can be accounted for by the rules, be reasonable.

  - These rules between survivors and xenonids are foremost intended to ensure survivors do not make intentional efforts kill many xenonids at the start of the round, assuming said xenonids also are making reasonable efforts to avoid being found by a survivor.\nThis does not however provide leeway for xenonids to stalk or search for survivors, or remain near gear, without risking being killed.
  - Survivors should not breach hive structures unrelated to paths towards loot, before 5 minutes have passed.
  - If you encounter a xenonid while looting or making your way to loot, you are free to attack them as they have forfeited their early round protection by being within the area.\nThis includes any cases where a xenonid is hiding anywhere reasonably near loot areas, where they would reasonably be safer avoiding the area.

  ## Metagaming/Powergaming/Etc

  - Do not hunt, move, or secure or otherwise interact with mapped animals that can be captured.\nThese creatures reduce the amount of xenonids at the start of the round.

  - Survivors may not complete marine objectives, such as collecting intel related objects, until they are rescued or have been enlisted into the marines.\nThis does not include repairing colony assets, such as power or communications, or recovering corpses using roleplay reasoning while doing so.

</Document>
