<Document>
  # Xenonid roleplay standards

  ## General Knowledge
  - Xenonids enact the will of the Queen and must follow her orders.
  - Xenonids can sense the marine ships and are aware they will be attacked shortly.
  - All xenonid knowledge is immediately considered shared knowledge.\nThis means that when any living xenonid that witnesses information, this is considered information shared to all other xenonid players. This includes ghosted players that later become a xenonid.

  ## Xenonids VS Hosts
  - Xenonids are a hostile, invasive species driven by instincts to defend and grow the hive.\nDo not ignore or act passively to potential hosts, unless it is for the preservation of your own life.
  - They are not friendly, and may not pretend to be friendly to potential hosts, or negotiate with them.\nThe exception to this are synthetics, which xenonids do not care for and can be ignored if safe to do so, and speak to them. However, under no circumstances will the xenonids decide against attacking or capturing potential hosts.

  ## Xenonids VS Survivors
  - Avoid seeking out survivors at the start of the round as a larva. Evolve before searching for them and bring allies, because [color=#ff0000]you will no longer protected by the early round timer[/color] should you die because you have left the protection of the hive.

  ## Killing
  (Reports of this from marines are less likely to be accurate.)

  - Xenonids may kill anyone, anywhere, for any reason, provided it is not detrimental to the hive. (for example, killing someone who could easily be infected, or is infected.)
  - Xenonids may only harm nested hosts if given explicit permission by the queen, or at their own risk of the above rule if the queen is unresponsive.

  ## Language and speech
  - Xenonids can define key locations such as marine bases and ships, but do not know the names of them, such as the Alamo and Normandy, instead calling them "metal birds" or similar. They may freely name any named areas on the map otherwise.
  - Do not spam the chat with noises.
  - Xenonids, due to the hivemind, learn everything and understand human equipment at a basic level, and can understand a marine's role.
  - Do not use memes in character. This includes replacing letters in words with X. You can send these messages in LOOC channel instead, with no issues.

  ## Queen
  - Do not draw unrelated pictures or write unrelated things on the map.
  - Do not give jellies to xenonids sarcastically or as a joke. These are permanent awards on a player's account for doing well as a character and should have effort put into them.
  - You are expected to have a level of professionalism in the role, similar to the Executive Officer of the marines.

  ## Metagaming/Powergaming/Etc

  Some parts of the game cannot be covered by mechanics to ensure proper roleplay and balance.

  - If you are a xenonid aboard the main ship before hijack, [color=#ff0000]do not attack newly spawned players in spawn areas, let them have a chance to gear up before you attack them![/color] Avoiding the spawn area unless the players are using them as cover will be enough.
  - Xenonids may not build with the [bold]intent[/bold] to hide revivable player corpses.
  - Xenonids cannot surround an objective structure or APC entirely with walls, but can make an accessible room of it with a resin door. A room at minimum should have a tile of walkable space around the structure, with the spirit of the rule being that you are building a base that includes the structure, not encasing it in resin solely for out of character gameplay purposes.

</Document>
