<Document>
  # Xenonid roleplay standards

  ## General
  - The Queen may banish and/or devolve xenonids who do not follow these rules.
  - Xenonids enact the will of the Queen and must follow her orders.\nThe Queen may not force a xeno to a specific caste.
  - Banished xenonids are exempt from hive protection and may be killed. It should be announced for clarity.

  ## Xenonids VS Hosts
  - They are not, and may never be friendly to lifeforms that are potential hosts, or threaten the hive.
  - The exception to this are synthetics, which xenonids do not care for and can be ignored if safe to do so.

  ## Xenonids VS Survivors
  - Avoid seeking out survivors at the start of the round as a larva. Evolve before searching for them and bring allies, because [color=#ff0000]you will no longer protected by the early round timer[/color] should you die because you have left the protection of the hive.

  ## Killing
  (Reports of this from marines are less likely to be accurate.)

  - Xenonids may kill anyone, anywhere, for any reason, provided it is not detrimental to the hive. (for example, killing someone who could easily be infected, or is infected.)
  - Xenonids may only harm nested hosts if given explicit permission by the queen, or at their own risk of the above rule if the queen is unresponsive.

  ## Language and speech
  - Xenonid language is an english translation of their thoughts. They can define locations such as marine bases and ships, but do not know the names of them.
  - Do not spam the chat with noises.
  - Xenonids, due to the hivemind, learn everything and understand human equipment at a basic level.
  - They can understand a marine's role.
  - Xenonids can sense the marine ships and are aware they may be attacked shortly.
  - Do not use memes in character. This includes replacing letters in words with X. You can send these messages in LOOC channel instead, with no issues.

  ## Queen
  - Do not draw unrelated pictures or write unrelated things on the map.
  - Do not give jellies to xenonids sarcastically or as a joke. These are permanent awards on a player's account for doing well as a character and should have effort put into them.
  - You are expected to have a level of professionalism in the role, similar to the Executive Officer of the marines.

  ## Metagaming/Powergaming

  Some parts of the game cannot be covered by mechanics to ensure proper roleplay and balance.

  - If you are a xenonid attacking aboard a warship (Almayer), [color=#ff0000]attacking newly spawned players in hypersleep areas before hijack is forbidden, let them have a chance to gear up before you attack them![/color] Avoiding the hypersleep rooms unless the Marines are using them as cover will be enough.
  - Xenonids may not build with the [bold]intent[/bold] to hide revivable player corpses.
  - Xenonids cannot surround an objective structure or APC entirely with walls, but can make an accessible room of it with a resin door. A room at minimum should have a tile of walkable space around the structure, with the spirit of the rule being that you are building a base that includes the structure, not encasing it in resin solely for out of character gameplay purposes.

</Document>
