<Document>
  # Xenonid roleplay standards

  ## General Knowledge
  - Xenonids enact the will of the Queen and must follow her orders.
  - Xenonids can sense the marine ships and are aware they will be attacked shortly.
  - All xenonid knowledge is immediately considered shared knowledge.\n\nThis means that when any living xenonid witnesses information, this information is considered shared to all other xenonid players. This includes ghosted players that later become a xenonid.

  ## Xenonids VS Hosts
  - Xenonids are a hostile, invasive species driven by instincts to defend and grow the hive.
  \nDo not ignore or act passively to potential hosts, unless it is for the preservation of your own life.
  - They are not friendly, and may not pretend to be friendly to potential hosts, or negotiate with them.
  \nThe exception to this are synthetics, which xenonids do not care for and if they wish, may ignore them if safe to do so, and speak to them. However, under no circumstances will the xenonids decide against attacking or capturing potential hosts.

  ## Killing
  (Reports of this from marines are less likely to be accurate.)

  - Xenonids may kill anyone, anywhere, for any reason, provided it would not be possible to capture them. It is preferred you capture hosts rather then kill them, unless it is outright not possible (lack of parasites, eggs, etc).\n\nDragging someone far away to kill them in an isolated spot takes the same amount of effort as capturing with the same end result of death, and generally does not serve any purpose.
  - Xenonids may only harm nested hosts if given explicit permission by the queen, or at their own risk of the above rule if the queen is unresponsive.\n\nThis can be done, if for example, the marines will reach the nested hosts faster than the xenonids can move them. Avoid killing a host solely because "they'll burst anyway" as this can and has resulted in lost larva, and may be considered faction sabotage.

  ## Language and speech
  - Xenonids can define key locations such as marine bases and ships, but do not know the names of them, such as the Alamo and Normandy, instead calling them "metal birds" or similar. They may freely name any named areas on the map otherwise.
  - Do not spam the chat with noises.
  - Xenonids, due to the hivemind, learn everything and understand human equipment at a basic level, and can understand a marine's role.
  - Do not use memes in character. This includes replacing letters in words with X. You can send these messages in LOOC channel instead, with no issues.

  ## Queen
  - The Queen may banish and/or devolve xenonids who do not follow these standards and expectations.\nBanished xenonids are exempt from hive protection and should be killed. It should be announced for clarity with the reason.
  - The Queen may not force a specific xenonid player to a specific caste, but may devolve any xenonid if there are too many of the same caste, to free an evolution tier slot for the sake better team composition.
  - Do not draw unrelated pictures or write unrelated things on the map.
  - Do not give jellies to xenonids sarcastically or as a joke. These are permanent awards on a player's account for doing well as a character and should have effort put into them.
  - You are expected to have a level of professionalism in the role, similar to the Executive Officer of the marines.

  ## Metagaming/Powergaming/Etc

  [bold]Some parts of the game cannot be covered by mechanics to ensure proper roleplay and balance:[/bold]

  - If you are a xenonid aboard the warship before hijack, [color=#ff0000]do not attack newly spawned players in spawn areas, let them have a chance to gear up before you attack them![/color] Avoiding the spawn area unless the players are using them as cover will be enough.
  - Xenonids may not encase revivable corpses, or objective structures/objects, but may build a surrounding room that contains it similar to regular defenses.
  \n\nA room at minimum should have a tile of walkable space around the subject, with the spirit of the rule being that you are building defenses that includes the subject behind them, and not entombing it in resin.\nExamples of objectives include but are not limited to sensors, communications, APCs

  [bold]NOT against rules:[/bold]

  - Xenonids may build in a way that disrupts a character. An example of this is a xenonid that remotely builds a wall on top of a living character to interrupt an action or movement.
  - A single wall does not typically obscure a corpse- a resin structure may sometimes need to be built on top of a corpse naturally for proper defenses to be made.


</Document>
