<Document>
  ## Don't antagonize others.
  You are playing a multiplayer game with other people who also want to enjoy the game.
  - Do not intentionally make other players' gameplay worse for your own amusement.\nIntentionally making yourself a major problem/annoyance/disruption for other players while not a hostile force is forbidden.
  - Give disconnected players at least 5-10 minutes (or until their character falls asleep) to return before considering taking their equipment or sending them to hypersleep.\nReturning to all your equipment being stolen or being removed from the round by your own team is not a good experience.
  - Do not take equipment from revivable dead players.
  - Avoid berating new players.\nThey cannot be expected to have full knowledge of the game, and should be taught rather than insulted.
  - Do not threaten or imply to players that you are reporting them.

  ### Roleplay Setting Disclaimer
  - We mandate a respectful environment OOC, however it must be recognized that characters in this setting are in high-stress scenarios and trying to murder each other. They will use colorful language, such as after a kill.
  \n\nInsults used in-character between opposing teams are permitted and expected; avoid assuming it is directed at you personally. Remember that you are either a xenonid that has destroyed a colony and mutilated its people, or a marine attacking their nest and killing their family.
  \n\nThis is not however an excuse to bypass server rules, for example those against slurs, hate speech, OOC toxicity, or other similar behavior, both real and fictional. These insults must strictly pertain to and remain in-character interactions, and must also not bleed OOC messages targeted against the player personally, be spam, or be excessive.
  \n\nAdmins will determine where the line is on a case by case basis.

  ## Crimes in Character

  Crimes must have sufficient in character motivation behind them, obtained during the round.

  - There is moderation leeway for minor crimes that benefit your character with a provided roleplay reason, which have consequences for your character if caught.
  - If you are caught, stay in character. Do not complain in any OOC channel.\nIt is not the fault of other players that consequences for your character happen - you are responsible for the actions you choose to take, and can avoid this by not breaking the law.
  - Disconnecting, making a mess of the brig, or excessively berating police when arrested can be used as evidence in lack of roleplaying behavior when doing crimes, for moderation purposes.\nAs a reminder, crimes require the character to have a motivation, and the player an intent to roleplay.
  - Do not consistently commit crimes across rounds (moderation's discretion), as this is very annoying to other players, a cause of ooc grudges, and almost never in character.
  - Players should not be charged more than once every 3 real days under normal gameplay, considering the server often exceeds 200 players with many of them being marines each round.

  ### Examples of invalid reasons for crimes:

  - "The MPs have nothing to do."
  - "I'm giving the MPs things to do."
  - Being bored.
  - Planning to commit a crime out of character before even joining the round.

  [bold]Other players have their own work and/or roleplay to do, or want to do, independent of everyone else at any given moment and do not need additional things to take care of, especially not from their own team.[/bold]

  ## Don't target players across rounds.
  Don't harass or target players across rounds for actions in prior rounds outside the game or in OOC.
  - Annoying a character, for in character reasons, while playing a character in the current round is fine; doing it across rounds is not.
  - Do not annoy or target players out of character for actions they took in any round.
</Document>
