<Document>
  # NON-Modifiable Third-Party Regulations

  Marines are encouraged to recover any third-party personnel found in the [bold]Area of Operations[/bold].

  ## General

  - Recovered personnel have the right to refuse questioning and must not be punished for invoking it.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] are not to detain civilian prisoners that are recovered unless they commit further crimes.
  - Third-party personnel should be given a medical examination, treatment if needed, and UNMC IFF to prevent incidents, if personnel are available. If done with reasonable speed, these requirements do not constitute an extended duration.

  ## Equipment and Searches

  - Third-party personnel intending to remain on the ship for an extended duration or leave the hangar, for example to enlist then obtain UNMC equipment or otherwise, must be searched by the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]. All weapons and unauthorized items must be secured within any nearby secure armory, whichever is most convenient for the personnel it belongs to.
  - Personnel that do not intend to remain on the ship for an extended period must not be searched without consent, but may not leave the dropship hangar for any reason.
  - They may keep their tools provided they are not used for crime.

  [bold]Enlisting[/bold]

  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may offer to enlist recovered personnel into combat positions should they have the qualifications, such as a rifleman, corpsman, or combat tech, under the rank of private. They are put under the same procedures, laws, and standards of the UNMC, and as such and allowed access to UNMC equipment.
  - These recovered personnel may also request the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] this opportunity.

  ## Returning to the AO

  - Recovered Personnel may request to be returned back to the [bold]Area of Operations[/bold] and their equipment to be returned. [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must, however, escort them back to the dropship to ensure they leave once their equipment is returned.
  - Returning again to the ship afterward, follows the same procedure regarding recovering personnel.

  ## Military and Paramilitary

  - Third-party military or paramilitary personnel may be allowed to continue their operations if they prove beneficial or indifferent to UNMC interests. (This is also located in the [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold])
  - They may be given permission to keep their weapons and equipment on the warship, provided they are beneficial to the operation.
  - They may also be denied access to the warship, and UNMC IFF.

  ## Prisoners of War

  Under normal circumstances, POWs are never to be executed.
  - They should be warned that escaping, or attempting to escape after a warning, will negate their protections and right to be treated and revived, and result in lethal force being used.
  - Attempts should be made to revive and treat members of other factions, where safe, but UNMC personnel are always of priority.

  A hostile member of a legitimate and recognised faction is considered a Prisoner of War if any of the below apply;
  - They surrender to UNMC forces.
  - They request and as of a result have received aid from UNMC personnel to any extent.
  - They are revived and taken into UNMC custody, with physical restraints.

  A Prisoner of War loses their status if any of the below apply;
  - The prisoner attempts to escape custody, after posing a threat to others prior to arrest and receiving a notice of their rights. They must be given the chance to surrender or stand down if they are not violent and escape is not imminent, but this is optional should they successfully escape or re-attempt to escape after being warned.
  - Any form of physical assault to UNMC personnel while in custody.

  ## Employment of Recovered Personnel

  Recovered civilians may be given a temporary position in a department relevant to their experience.

  [bold]General[/bold]

  - Employed personnel must be given an ID identifying them in their new position with access to their work area.
  - Employed personnel are below all personnel in assigned departments, and must obey orders.
  - Personnel not part of the [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] or Military Police of the UN must not be given a position in the Military Police.

  ## Eviction

  Recovered personnel may be evicted and denied access to the ship by the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], and [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color], where the higher ranking person may overrule the other.

  - Recovered personnel may be evicted if they commit any major crime.
  - A [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color] is unable to request an eviction, except where a crime done by the person is of a violent nature.

</Document>
