<Document>
  # Department Regulations

  Regulations of specific departments, excluding non-modifiable regulations are listed here. The head of the department holds responsibility for it and answers directly to the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] of the ship.

  - [bold]Department Heads[/bold] are not to deploy to the [bold]AO[/bold], except the [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold] (under circumstances listed in the engineering section.)
  - Any crew that intend to deploy, including [bold]Staff Officer[/bold]s, require permission from either the head of their department or the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], where the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] can overrule the department head.

  ## Medical

  - The [bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold] has final say over the medbay and medical operations aboard the warship, except when overridden by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].
  - They may authorize or prohibit experiments at their discretion, and set medbay procedures.
  - They may only fire medbay staff in the case they have performed crime.
  - When in medbay, all personnel, excluding the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], are required to listen to and obey the orders of the [bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold].
  - During code [bold][color=black]Delta[/color][/bold], medical personnel are to either escape in pods and evacuate the ship, or hold in [bold]Secure Area[/bold]s with the marines to provide medical support.
  - Pills must be kept within pill bottles.
  - All reagent-containing medical equipment, such as syringes, pill bottles, and autoinjectors must be labelled with accurate contents and dosing information. Vended or otherwise existing medicine not created by personnel do not have to be relabeled unless the contents are modified.
  - Surgery tools and other medical devices when not in use must be placed within their designated containers.

  ## Requisitions

  - No equipment may be taken from requisitions by non-requisitions personnel without the [bold]Logistics Officer[/bold]'s approval.
  - Requisitions personnel may refuse to provide service if a valid reason is provided, such as a civilian attempting to request grenades from the weapons supply. The decision may be overridden by the [bold]Logistics Officer[/bold] or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]
  - The [bold]Logistics Officer[/bold] has control over the requisitions bay and the right to decline service to any personnel, including officers. Any order to provide or decline service, including orders relating to the management of the operational budget, may be ignored.
  - Their decisions on such matters may only be overridden by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].
  - During code [bold][color=black]Delta[/color][/bold], the requisitions department is to follow orders from command. All requisitions personnel are to join the marines in either holding the warship, or assisting with evacuation of civilians, depending on the orders of command.
  - The [bold]Logistics Officer[/bold] has control over the kitchen and [bold]Mess Technicians[/bold] assigned to it.
  - [bold]Mess Technicians[/bold] are not required to provide service to anyone if they provide a valid reasoning, such as rudeness.

  ## Engineering

  - The [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold] is in charge of modifications made to the ship as well as performing repairs, and maintenance.
  - The [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold] is still required to follow the ship modifications section of SOP.
  - The [bold]Auxiliary Support Officer[/bold] holds authority over the [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold].
  - The ordnance technicians are part of the engineering department.
  - During code [bold][color=black]Delta[/color][/bold], the engineering department is to follow orders from command. All engineering personnel are to join the marines in either holding the warship, or assisting with evacuation of civilians, depending on the orders of command.

  ## Dropships and Gunships

  - The designated [bold]Pilot[/bold]s of these ships are responsible for them and any modifications made to them.
  - [bold]Pilot[/bold]s may modify or delegate modifications to their ships without requesting permission. However, these modifications may be overwritten by the [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold] or [bold]Auxiliary Support Officer[/bold].
  - Dismantling ship parts to utilize materials for operational use is strictly forbidden.
  - Ship doors must remain intact and easily accessible.
  - Dropship seating must remain intact and easily accessible.
  - Gunship seating may be reduced to accommodate additional ammunition storage, but it may not be removed entirely. Any remaining seating must remain easily accessible.
  - If the dropship is inaccessible or otherwise inoperable, the gunship must serve as the dropship and be equipped with the necessary seating.
  - If parachute drops are being utilized, the [bold]Flight Crew[/bold] is responsible for ensuring the drop location is safe (unless directed otherwise by CIC staff) and informing the personnel when to exit the ship.
  - Enlisted personnel (excluding [bold]Flight Crew[/bold]) are not permitted in ship cockpits unless in an emergency.
  - [bold]Flight Crew[/bold] have the authority to remove disruptive personnel from their ship. If a person refuses to leave or repeatedly returns, they may be charged with [bold]Trespassing[/bold] and arrested by the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]. They may only return to the ship if ordered to deploy and must remain well-behaved, or they will be additionally charged with [bold]Disorderly Conduct[/bold] and [bold]Major Insubordination[/bold].

</Document>
