<Document>
  # NON-Modifiable Command SOP

  ## Operations

  Operations are considered ended when the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] announces such, and it is their responsibility to inform all personnel.

  Some examples of cases where an operation can be considered ended include:

  - The [bold]AO[/bold] is safe and secure, personnel are no longer needed and may be relieved to rest.
  - Evacuation of the [bold]AO[/bold] has occured, with no intent to return.

  ## Areas

  ### Forward Operating Base

  The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] in charge of an operation must take the minimum precautions to ensure security and defense for stationed personnel, and incoming transport, when designating a [bold]Forward Operating Base[/bold].

  - The [bold]FOB[/bold] must be a [bold]Secure Area[/bold] and designated by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].
  - The [bold]Primary Landing Zone[/bold] still requires its outlined defenses, regardless of where the [bold]FOB[/bold] is designated.
  - The [bold]Primary Landing Zone[/bold] is assumed to be the [bold]FOB[/bold] if not designated elsewhere.


  ### Secure Areas

  - Must be designated by [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold].
  - It must be reinforced with a minimum of a surrounding line of non-makeshift barricades, and where there has been no recent combat or threats.
  - Additional areas may be designated as [bold]Secure Areas[/bold] by any [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold]. Their secure status may be revoked for any reason by any [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold]. It should be announced in both cases for clarity.
  - These areas dictate where certain shipside personnel are allowed to be given permission to work safely.
  - [bold]Secure Areas[/bold] that have had their innermost barricades attacked are presumed no longer secure, and should be reported for safety. Relevant personnel should be escorted from the area if the safety and status of the area cannot be restored.

  ### Field Hospital

  - Must be designated by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] or [bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold], and must also be able to be considered a [bold]Secure Area[/bold] by either person.
  - It is the only area aside from the [bold]FOB[/bold] in the [bold]AO[/bold] that the [bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold] or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may give permission to doctors and nurses to move to.
  - This should be announced for clarity.


  ### Primary Landing Zone

  - Selected for the entire duration of the operation by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].
  - The primary landing zone must be reinforced with a minimum of a surrounding line of non-makeshift barricades, including stationed marines.
  - It can be presumed by all personnel to be a [bold]Secure Area[/bold] regardless of barricades, while deployed gauss turret systems are still active during the initial phase of the operation.
  - Only Bravo may be stationed as the primary landing zone and [bold]FOB[/bold]'s primary defense. Any additional squads may assist where needed, and combat technicians may also be ordered to help reinforce the [bold]FOB[/bold] and primary landing zone defenses before resuming their original squad's orders.

  ## Conduct of Briefing

  The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] is to ensure a proper briefing before any operation is being held and personnel deployed.
  - It may be skipped in the event of a code [bold][color=black]Delta[/color][/bold] or another emergency situation of the same severity.
  - A briefing should generally be completed before fueling is completed for an operation, unless there are circumstances to resolve that would delay it.

  ### Location

  - Brief must be performed in an area where a proper inspection of personnel can be held and where personnel can hear any orders.
  - Areas that interfere with non-combat personnel must be avoided, for example the medbay.

  ### Personnel Requirements

  - Briefings at minimum must include the Squad Leaders.
  - Briefings at minimum must include [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold], unless the [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold] are performing other essential roles at the time, and may be excused by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] at their discretion. Notify the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] beforehand.

  ### Scouts and Intel

  - Scout Specialists and Intelligence Squad members may deploy before the general briefing, if all members have a collective briefing of their orders and are ready to deploy.

  ## High Ranking Officers
  UNMC Officers ranked [bold]Major[/bold] or above but are not already the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] of the warship receive these rights:
  - The same arrest immunities normally granted to the warship's [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color].
  - The right to accept being appointed as the warship [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]. This does not also mean they have to be the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] of the current operation.
  - The right to assign themselves the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] position of the warship if the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] would need to be replaced as defined by "[textlink="Definitions" link="RMCMarineLawDefinitions"]", becoming the new [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] as well.

  ## Deputizing

  When deputized, these personnel are expected and required to follow Marine Law like an [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color], and will carry the same punishments.

  The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may deputize the following personnel to make arrests and enforce Marine Law, should [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s be unavailable or unable to respond in a timely manner.
  - The Executive Officer.
  - The Auxiliary Support Officer.
  - Staff Officers.
  - UNMC Synthetics.
  - Department Heads.

  ### Approval Required

  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may freely deputize under the above conditions.
  - Any other [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] must also obtain the approval of the current [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color], unless it is not currently possible to assign an acting [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color].

</Document>
