<Document>
  # NON-Modifiable Third-Party Regulations

  Marines are encouraged to recover any third-party personnel found in the [bold]Area of Operations[/bold].

  ## General

  - Recovered personnel have the right to refuse questioning and must not be punished for invoking it.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] are not to detain civilian prisoners that are recovered unless they commit further crimes.
  - Third-party personnel, if they request it, should be given a medical examination, treatment if needed, and UNMC IFF. If done with reasonable speed, these requirements do not constitute an extended duration.
  - They may not be provided any UNMC medical or general equipment, such as medicine and weapons, until they become [bold]contracted[/bold].

  ## Military and Paramilitary

  - [bold]Military[/bold] is defined as any military personnel of another nation; soldiers, medics, officers, etc.
  - [bold]Paramilitary[/bold] is defined as any personnel or mercenaries part of an organization that conducts combat or defensive combat as a service. This does not include civilian security services or civilian law enforcement.
  - Both types of personnel may be allowed to continue their operations in the AO if they prove beneficial or indifferent to UNMC interests. (This is also located in the [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold])
  - Both types of personnel may be given permission to keep their weapons and equipment while on the warship by any [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color], provided the personnel are beneficial to the operation.

  ## Equipment and Searches

  - Unless they intend to become contracted, third-party personnel intending to remain on the warship for an extended duration or leave the hangar, must be searched by the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color].\nIn this case, all weapons and unauthorized items must be secured within any nearby secure armory, whichever is most convenient for the personnel it belongs to.
  - Personnel that do not intend to remain on the warship for an extended period must not be searched without consent, but may not leave the dropship hangar for any reason, unless they intend to be contracted.
  - They may keep tools provided they are not used for crime.

  ## Contracting

  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] should offer to contract and deploy recovered personnel into combat positions should they have the qualifications, such as a rifleman, corpsman, or combat tech, for temporary military operations, which through the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]s orders, may be offered and processed by any available [bold]Officer[/bold] or [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] in their stead.\n\nThey will be put under the same procedures, laws, and standards of the UNMC, and as such are given temporary access to UNMC equipment, and permission to retain all their personal and requisition provided equipment aboard the warship, while they are providing service to the UNMC.\n\nPayment for services provided will be negotiated when the warship docks at the next safe port.
  - Civilians and Military of other nations may not be contracted, unless they are defecting to the United Nations, and will be considered refugees.\nThey may be contracted after this point, if they are considered reliable, not a security risk, and are not exhibiting hostile behaviors to United Nations personnel.

  ## Returning to the AO

  - Recovered personnel that are not contracted may request to be returned back to the [bold]Area of Operations[/bold] and their equipment to be returned. [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must, however, escort them back to the dropship to ensure they leave once their equipment is returned.
  - Returning again to the warship afterward, follows the same procedure regarding recovering personnel, unless they are contracted.

  ## Prisoners of War

  [bold]Under normal circumstances, POWs are never to be executed.[/bold]
  - They should be warned that escaping, or attempting to escape after a warning, will negate their protections and right to be treated and revived, and result in lethal force being used.
  - Attempts should be made to revive and treat members of other nations, where safe, but UNMC personnel are always of priority.

  [bold]A hostile member of a legitimate and recognised nation is considered a Prisoner of War if any of the below apply;[/bold]

  - They surrender to UNMC forces.
  - They request and as of a result have received aid from UNMC personnel to any extent.
  - They are revived and taken into UNMC custody, with physical restraints.
  - Any civilians recognised to be part of, or otherwise bearing the colors or insignia of the alleged "CLF" threat are to be treated as Prisoners of War.\nThey should be transferred to the nearest Colony Marshal Bureau outpost for processing, as soon as the warship no longer has any urgent orders or operations ongoing.

  [bold]A Prisoner of War loses their status if any of the below apply;[/bold]

  - The prisoner attempts to escape custody, after posing a threat to others prior to arrest and receiving a notice of their rights. They must be given the chance to surrender or stand down if they are not violent and escape is not imminent, but this is optional should they successfully escape or re-attempt to escape after being warned.
  - Any form of physical assault to UNMC personnel while in custody.

  ## Employment of Recovered Personnel

  Recovered civilians may be given a temporary position in a department relevant to their experience.

  [bold]General[/bold]

  - Employed personnel must be given an ID identifying them in their new position with access to their work area.
  - Employed personnel are below all personnel in assigned departments, and must obey orders.
  - Personnel not part of the [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] or Military Police of the UN must not be given a position in the Military Police.

  ## Eviction

  Recovered personnel may be evicted and denied access to the warship by the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], and [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color], where the higher ranking person may overrule the other.

  - Recovered personnel may be evicted if they commit any major crime.

</Document>
