<Document>
  # NON-Modifiable Command SOP

  ## Forward Operating Bases

  The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] in charge of an operation must take the minimum precautions to ensure security and defense for stationed personnel, and incoming transport, when designating a [bold]Forward Operating Base[/bold].

  - The [bold]FOB[/bold] must be a [bold]Secure Area[/bold] and designated by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].
  - The [bold]FOB[/bold] does not have to be placed adjacent to a landing zone, but the primary landing zone still requires its outlined defenses.
  - Only Bravo may be stationed as the primary landing zone and [bold]FOB[/bold]'s primary defense. Any additional squads may assist where needed, and combat technicians may also be ordered to help reinforce the [bold]FOB[/bold] and primary landing zone defenses before resuming their original squad's orders.

  ## Secure Areas

  - Additional areas may be designated as [bold]Secure Area[/bold]s by any [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold]. These are not considered a [bold]FOB[/bold], and their secure status may be revoked for any reason by any [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold].
  - These areas dictate where certain shipside personnel are allowed to be given permission to work.
  - These areas are no longer secure if there is a breach or the area is being attacked by hostiles.

  ## Field hospitals

  - It must be designated as a [bold]Secure Area.[/bold]
  - The field hospital must be designated as such by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] or [bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold].


  ## Primary Landing Zones

  - Selected for the entire duration of the operation by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].
  - The primary landing zone must be reinforced with a minimum of a line of non-makeshift defenses, including stationed marines.

  ## Conduct of Briefing

  The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] is to ensure a proper briefing before any operation is being held and personnel deployed, but may be skipped in the event of a code [bold][color=black]Delta[/color][/bold] or another emergency situation of the same severity.

  Scout Specialists and Intelligence Squad members may deploy before the operation begins, if all members have a collective briefing of their orders and are ready to deploy before the main briefing.

  - It must be performed in an area where a proper inspection of personnel can be held and where personnel can hear any orders.
  - Areas that interfere with non-combat personnel must be avoided, for example the medbay.
  - Briefings at minimum must include the Squad Leaders.
  - Briefings at minimum must include [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold], unless the [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold] are performing other essential roles at the time, and may be excused by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] at their discretion if the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] are notified beforehand.
  - Failure to adhere to attend the briefing when required as stated above will incur [bold]Neglect of Duty[/bold] charges.

  ## High Ranking Officers
  UNMC Officers ranked [bold]Major[/bold] or above but are not already the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] of the ship receive these rights:
  - The same arrest immunities normally granted to the ship [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color].
  - The right to accept being appointed as the ship [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].
  - The right to take the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] position of the ship if the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] would need to be replaced as defined by "[textlink="Definitions" link="RMCMarineLawDefinitions"]", becoming the new [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] as well.

  ## Deputizing

  When deputized, these personnel are expected and required to follow Marine Law like an [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color], and will carry the same punishments.

  The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may deputize the following personnel to make arrests and enforce Marine Law, should [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color]s be unavailable or unable to respond in a timely manner.
  - The Executive Officer.
  - The Auxiliary Support Officer.
  - Staff Officers.
  - UNMC Synthetics.
  - Department Heads.

  The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may deputize under the above conditions, however any other [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] must also obtain the approval of the current [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color], unless it is not currently possible to assign an acting [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color].

</Document>
