<Document>
  # NON-Modifiable Third-Party Regulations

  Marines are encouraged to recover any third-party personnel found in the [bold]Area of Operations[/bold].

  ## General

  - All recovered personnel must be searched on arrival by the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color], with all weapons and unauthorized items secured within the brig. They may keep their tools provided they are not used for crime.
  - They should be given a medical examination if personnel are available.
  - Recovered personnel have the right to remain silent and must not be punished for invoking it.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] are not required to detain civilian prisoners that are recovered.

  ## Military and Paramilitary

  - Third-party military or paramilitary personnel may be allowed to continue their operations if they prove beneficial or indifferent to UNMC interests. (This is also located in the [bold]Rules of Engagement[/bold])
  - They may be given permission to keep their weapons and equipment on the warship, provided they are beneficial to the operation.
  - They may also be denied access to the warship.

  ## Prisoners of War

  Under normal circumstances, POWs are never to be executed.
  - They should be warned that escaping will negate their protections and right to be treated and revived, and result in lethal force being used.
  - Attempts should be made to revive and treat members of other factions, where safe, but UNMC personnel are always of priority.

  A hostile member of a legitimate and recognised faction is considered a Prisoner of War if any of the below apply;
  - They surrender to UNMC forces.
  - They request and as of a result have received aid from UNMC personnel to any extent.
  - They are revived and taken into UNMC custody, with physical restraints.

  A Prisoner of War loses their status if any of the below apply;
  - The prisoner successfully escapes custody, after posing a threat to others prior to arrest and receiving a warning. They may still be given the chance to surrender if they are not violent, but this is optional.
  - Any form of physical assault to UNMC personnel while in custody.

  ## Returning to the AO

  - Recovered Personnel may deploy back to the [bold]Area of Operations[/bold] and request their equipment be returned. [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must, however, escort them back to the dropship to ensure they deploy.
  - Returning from this deployment requires another search, but medical examinations may be skipped.

  ## Employment of Recovered Personnel

  Recovered civilians may be given a temporary position in a department relevant to their experience.

  [bold]General[/bold]

  - Employed personnel must be given an ID identifying them in their new position with access to their work area.
  - Employed personnel are below all personnel in assigned departments, and must obey orders.
  - Personnel not part of the [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] or Military Police of the UN must not be given a position in the Military Police.

  [bold]Enlisting[/bold]

  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may offer to enlist recovered personnel into combat positions should they have the qualifications, such as a rifleman, corpsman, or combat tech, under the rank of private.
  - A [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color] is unable to enlist recovered personnel.

  ## Eviction

  Recovered personnel may be evicted and denied access to the ship by the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], and [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color], where the higher ranking person may overrule the other.

  - Recovered personnel may be evicted if they commit any major crime.
  - A [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color] is unable to request an eviction, except where a crime done by the person is of a violent nature.

</Document>
