<Document>
  # General Regulations

  ## Rules of Engagement

  The following are the standard rules of engagement, and may be modified by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] as necessary as the operation proceeds.

  - Any useful equipment found within the AO such as weapons or tools may be requisitioned for operational use by any UNMC personnel.
  - Buildings and obstacles within the AO may be constructed/deconstructed for strategic or tactical function. The use of explosives is authorized for demolitions.
  - Wildlife not part of the operation may not be needlessly hunted if passive. Wildlife that approaches [bold]Secure Area[/bold]s or compromises the personal space of marines or their formations, or are otherwise hostile may be shot.
  - Any sapient life that is not overtly hostile must be halted and questioned of their intentions. Survivors are to be debriefed and given the option to board the warship as a passenger, and can be offered this freely.
  - Any non-UNMC military or paramilitary personnel may be allowed to continue their operations if they prove beneficial or indifferent to UNMC operations or interests.
  - The use of force is authorized to disable non-compliant personnel.
  - Hostile personnel deemed a threat to UNMC personnel may be killed on sight, unless they are surrendering.

  ## Communications
  - Communications over UNMC radio and announcements should be done in plain English to maintain clear and concise communication. Other languages* and speech forms may be used freely outside this. [italic](*Other languages meaning languages provided by the game mechanics, and not written by the player in another language.)[/italic]

  ## Ship Modifications and Dismantling

  The ship may only be modified with approval from the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]. The [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold] can also approve changes to the ship, unless it affects another department, which would also require approval from the department head.

  - A [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color] is unable to authorize ship modifications.
  - The [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must be notified of changes being made [bold]prior[/bold] to them taking effect.
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] has final word over changes to the ship.
  - Changes to the brig and CIC that compromise security of these areas are forbidden.
  - Any personnel may fax [color=#ffa500][bold]Provost Marshal Office[/bold][/color] to contest a decision made by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] about dismantling the ship. If these changes are prior to hostile contacts, [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may take action against the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], following regular procedure.
  - Removal of vendors or machines is not illegal modification unless it alters the function or purpose of the area they are taken from.
  - Dismantling ship parts to utilize materials for operational use is strictly forbidden unless severe enemy contact is confirmed, and where significantly more resources are required than on hand.
  - The deconstruction of crates and barrels are not considered ship modifications.

</Document>
