<Document>
  # NON-Modifiable Deployment Restrictions

  ## Nuclear Protocol

  In the event of nuclear ordnance being deployed, all personnel are authorized to deploy to the [bold]FOB[/bold] to protect it during countdown, which overrides all other department SOP preventing deployments. Instead, the following restrictions apply:

  - The following staff must remain shipside, unless stated otherwise by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]: A [bold]Doctor or Chief Medical Officer[/bold], one member of [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold], and additionally the [bold]Military Warden[/bold] or [bold]Chief MP[/bold] if a prisoner is currently in brig.
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may order personnel to remain aboard the ship at their discretion.
  - Prisoners may not be deployed.

  ## Command Field Deployment

  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] and [bold]Executive Officer[/bold] have the exclusive, non-transferable right to deploy to the frontline for the sake of commanding their personnel from a direct point of view.
  - Deployments must be for the sake of the personnel and operation, and not for the personal glory.
  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] and [bold]Executive Officer[/bold] must not be deployed at the same time, if both are present.

  [bold]Preparing to Deploy[/bold]

  - Deployment must not be done unless they are confident CIC can be managed in their absence.
  - Actions taken by [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold] during the absence is the responsibility of the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], not the [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color].
  - If the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] is present, the [bold]Executive Officer[/bold] requires permission to deploy.
  - Both must notify [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold] of their intent to deploy.

  [bold]When Deployed[/bold]

  - A deploying [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] must still command and communicate frequently with both the [bold]CIC[/bold] and marine crews.
  - Combat should be reserved when assisting the marines in a supporting capacity, in defense of others and self, or directly leading an offensive maneuver.
  - They should avoid unnecessarily putting themselves in danger, and remain close to marines to focus on providing clear orders.

  ## Shipside Personnel

  Personnel normally restricted to shipside duties such as doctors and Military Police may be deployed to the [bold]FOB[/bold]; however special circumstances or clearances are needed.

  - A [color=#90EE90][bold]Duty Officer[/bold][/color] may not deploy.
  - Civilians (Personnel that are not enlisted or officers of the UNMC) may deploy at their discretion, provided their landing zone is not in direct danger.
  - All recovered personnel defined by [textlink="NON-Modifiable Third-Party Personnel" link="RMCMarineSOPNONModThirdparty"] do not require permission to deploy.
  - [bold]Department Heads[/bold] may not deploy at all, except the [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold] under some conditions.
  - All personnel that intend to deploy, including [bold]Staff Officer[/bold]s require permission from either their head of department, or the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may overrule the department head regarding deployment.

  [bold]Engineering[/bold]

  - The [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold] may deploy to the [bold]FOB[/bold] if there is an [bold]Auxiliary Support Officer[/bold] on board, but still requires permission from them or the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].
  - Both the [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold] and maintenance techs may only deploy with the purpose of building the [bold]FOB[/bold], and telecommunications, but must leave if these areas are no longer considered secure.

  [bold]Medical[/bold]

  - Doctors and Nurses may deploy to the [bold]FOB[/bold], and designated [bold]Field Hospital[/bold], until they are no longer [bold]Secure Area[/bold]s.

  [bold]Requisitions[/bold]

  - Requisitions Technicians may deploy to the [bold]FOB[/bold] to assist in organizing and accounting for supplies.

  [bold]Military Police[/bold]

  See [textlink="Field Arrests" link="RMCMarineLawArresting"] for more information.

  - [bold]CIC Personnel[/bold] may request up to four volunteers from the [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] to be deployed to the [bold]AO[/bold], keeping within the [bold]FOB[/bold] and [bold]Secure Area[/bold]s to protect deployed shipside personnel and handle law.
  - This is unrelated to [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] escorts, and can be overridden by either higher ranking personnel or the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].
  - At least one [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must remain on the ship at all times. If the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] is present, it must be them.
  - The [bold]Warden[/bold] may deploy to handle law in the absence of [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] officers, but must otherwise remain on the ship.
  - Deployed [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may move between any [bold]Secure Area[/bold]s and should be avoiding combat while doing so, unless it is in protection of non-combat personnel like doctors or themselves.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must retreat and assist non-combat personnel in retreating from any [bold]Secure Area[/bold] or the [bold]FOB[/bold] if it is no longer secure.


</Document>
