<Document>
  # NON-Modifiable Department Regulations

  ## Restricted Areas and Access Modification

  ## Armories

  - Special equipment found in armories such as the M890 Tactical Shotgun are not allowed to be handed out to non-officers without a clear, understandable, and urgent reason. The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]'s weapons may also not be handed out.
  - Equipment stored in armories may not be part of a supply drop, rewards or prizes, and may not be used to form a squad.
  - Armory equipment may be given to all personnel during a Code [bold][color=red]Red[/color][/bold] or Code [bold][color=black]Delta[/color][/bold] scenario. Officers must be prioritized before enlisted.

  ## AI Core

  The AI Core is the direct responsibility of any active AI Service Technician assigned to the ship. They are authorized to remove any personnel present in the core excluding pre-authorized personnel listed in the Access section. In the absence of one, the responsibility is the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]'s, then the [Bold]Chief Engineer[/Bold].

  [bold]Access[/bold]
  - Access to the AI core is strictly by appointment only.
  - Only UNMC synthetics, AI Service technicians (Including WEYA technicians), the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], and the [Bold]Chief Engineer[/Bold] have free access.
  - Prior to any authorized appointments, weapons should be deposited at the reception desk and returned after the appointment has concluded.
  - Anyone bringing weapons into the AI Core lose their right to access it and may result in Core Security Protocol being engaged. Pre-authorized personnel and [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] responding to a legitimate security threat are excempt.
  - Access rights are not transferable. Only UNMC Synthetics, AI Service Techs, and ARES may grant access to the AI core, through access requests.

  [bold]AI Core Security Protocol[/bold]

  ARES is equipped with various tools to ensure the AI Core remains safe during emergencies.

  - ARES, through UNMC Synthetics, is authorized to remove trespassers by physical force.
  - Circumstances that pose a serious threat to the integrity of the AI Core, ARES or UNMC Synthetics may initiate a core lockdown, resulting in all access routes being sealed and automated sentry guns located in the core chamber being armed.
  - If lockdown procedures are ineffective or compromised, nerve gas may be deployed from vents to incapacitate intruders.

  ## Military Police

  [bold]Use of listening devices[/bold]
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] are authorized to use their provided listening devices within the brig at their discretion.

  Any use of these devices outside of the brig must follow these requirements;
  - They must revieve permission from the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], or in their absence the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color].
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may only authorize use if there is reasonable suspicion of intent to or conspiracy to commit a crime in that area.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may not break or enter, nor have someone else do so, into an area they do not have access to in order to place devices.

</Document>
