<Document>
  # Equipment Regulations

  ## Command Related

  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may issue special equipment on a case by case basis, such as special headsets or special weaponry for certain marines or squads as long as it does not violate Marine Law.
  - Heads of staff may also assign spare non-command headsets to members of their department.
  - The Command tablet may only be taken by the current [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], unless they are offering it to someone else who would need it, such as a deploying [bold]Executive Officer[/bold].
  - [bold]High Ranking Officers[/bold] can be granted a Command headset if requested.

  ## Mess - Alcohol

  - Alcohol may only be carried or stored in the officer's mess, [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]'s mess, [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]'s quarters, and a civilian's private quarters, if applicable.
  - Any person found with alcohol outside these areas will have it confiscated, and if provided to UNMC personnel during duty will be considered [bold]Aiding and Abetting[/bold]: [bold]Intoxication[/bold].
  - Intoxication is only a crime before and during active operations.

  ## Uniform Regulations

  Personnel are required to be wearing appropriate clothing during operations to be identifiable to civilians and allies. SOP may not be changed to allow personnel to deploy without clothes or uniform.

  - Deploying marine squads must be wearing their uniform and boots at minimum.
  - Squad leaders, fireteam leaders, specialists, and smart gun operators must use helmets or cameras if the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] orders it.

  ### Shipside Personnel

  - Shipside personnel must wear their uniform and assigned footwear, or a [bold]Standard Issue[/bold] replacement.
  - Shipside personnel, except [bold]Intelligence Officers[/bold] and [bold]Flight Crew[/bold] should not be in armor unless the warship's code restriction allows it, or they are deploying.\n\nAnyone provided a M3-XL pattern armor vest in their personal equipment rack may wear it at all times.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] must be wearing their protective armor at all times. They may temporarily remove it after an operation has ended for social events, such as memorials.

  ### Department Gear

  - Department specific uniforms, headgear, and communications should only be given to personnel within that department, unless provided permission by the department head or [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color].

  ## Equipment Handling Regulations

  - Weapons should be holstered when not in use. Personnel must be allowed to holster on their first offense.
  - Under normal circumstances, weapons may only be fired in the firing range.
  - Training equipment like training grenades and training ammunition must only be used in firing ranges, or controlled areas approved by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] or [bold]Senior Enlisted Advisor.[/bold]
  - The [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] or [bold]Warden[/bold] may authorise use of [bold]riot equipment[/bold] within the brig for training or defensive purposes.

  ## Gear in AO

  - Any [bold]useful[/bold] equipment found within the [bold]AO[/bold] such as weapons, tools, armor, and other general gear may be requisitioned for operational use by any UNMC personnel.
  - Any non-standard issue clothing or armor from the [bold]AO[/bold] should not be worn if participating in social events such as memorials.\n\nThis requisitioned equipment should be returned to its owners or original location where relevant after the [bold]AO[/bold] is considered safe, or the owners will be compensated by the United Nations.

  ## Weapon Regulations - Deployment

  - Deploying [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may carry all [bold]Standard Issue[/bold] weapons, provided they are used in escorting and protecting non-combat personnel, or are escorts of the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color].
  - Deploying combat personnel and [bold]Officers[/bold] excluding medical personnel may carry all [bold]Standard Issue[/bold] weapons.
  - Deploying non-combat personnel may carry a sidearm.

  ## Weapon Regulations - Shipside Codes

  Weapon use and possession is allowed if you or someone you are responsible for are in immediate, life-threatening danger and the appropriate code-level has not been set. Code definitions can be found in the definitions page.

  Code [bold][color=lightgreen]Green[/color][/bold]:

  - Personnel provided weapons through their vendors at the start of an operation as well as weapons they emerge from hypersleep with may retain them.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may carry Non-lethals and sidearms, excluding [bold]riot equipment[/bold].
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may carry flashbangs, but may only use them in self-defense or defense of others.
  - [bold]Officer[/bold]s may carry sidearms as long as it does not inhibit their duties.
  - Long or large bladed weapons are treated the same as firearms in carry restrictions.
  - Shipside civilians are excluded from the right to retain provided weapons unless they are deploying to the [bold]AO[/bold]. These weapons should otherwise be kept secure in personal quarters or any shipside armory.
  - Personnel who abuse their right to a firearm can have this right revoked by the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color]. The [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color] may also do this if the person is ranked lower or is a civilian.


  Code [bold][color=lightblue]Blue[/color][/bold]:

  - All capable people may be provided sidearms, and retain them.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may carry lethal primary weapons to subdue external threats.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may use non-lethal [bold]riot equipment[/bold] to subdue marines during a mutiny or large gatherings of insubordinate personnel.

  Code [bold][color=red]Red[/color][/bold]:

  - All capable personnel may be temporarily provided [bold]Standard Issue[/bold] primary weapons until the threat is subdued.
  - Armory equipment may be given to all shipside crew for self-defense until the threat is subdued. UNMC Officers must be prioritized.

  Code [bold][color=black]Delta[/color][/bold]:

  - All weapons, are authorised to be used by any capable person.

</Document>
