<Document>
  # NON-Modifiable Department and Equipment

  ## Job Specific Equipment

  - Equipment, clothing, and any similar items from personal job-specific vendors may not be awarded or otherwise handed out.
  - The only exceptions to this is [bold]Standard Issue[/bold] equipment that can be obtained through requisitions normally, or is equipment specifically intended to be used by another designated person, such as spotter equipment from a sniper specialist being given to a rifleman that is becoming a spotter.

  ## Armories

  Armory equipment is unrelated other equipment, and has its own regulations. Armory equipment is intended to supply and provide protection for shipside personnel during shipside emergencies.

  - Armory equipment may only be given to all personnel during a Code [bold][color=red]Red[/color][/bold] or Code [bold][color=black]Delta[/color][/bold] scenario. Officers must be prioritized before enlisted.
  - Equipment stored in armories such as M890 Tactical Shotguns and ballistics vests are not allowed to be handed out without a clear, understandable, and urgent reason. Deployment is not an urgent reason.
  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]'s weapons may also not be handed out.
  - Equipment stored in armories may not be part of a supply drop, rewards or prizes, and may not be used to form a squad.

  This list of equipment stored within armories may, regardless of the above, be used for deployment:

  - The UNMC and UN flag.
  - All provided tents.
  - Honor Guard kits, provided they are used within their own restrictions.
  - [bold]Staff Officer[/bold] Armory Weapon Racks.

  ## AI Core

  The AI Core is the direct responsibility of any active AI Service Technician assigned to the ship. They are authorized to remove any personnel present in the core excluding pre-authorized personnel listed in the Access section. In the absence of one, the responsibility is the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color]'s, then the [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold].

  [bold]Access[/bold]
  - Access to the AI core is strictly by appointment only.
  - Only UNMC synthetics, AI Service technicians (Including WEYA technicians), the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color], and the [bold]Chief Engineer[/bold] have free access.
  - Prior to any authorized appointments, weapons should be deposited at the reception desk and returned after the appointment has concluded.
  - Anyone bringing weapons into the AI Core lose their right to access it and may result in Core Security Protocol being engaged. Pre-authorized personnel and [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] responding to a legitimate security threat are exempt.
  - Access rights are not transferable. Only UNMC Synthetics, AI Service Techs, and ARES may grant access to the AI core, through access requests.

  [bold]AI Core Security Protocol[/bold]

  ARES is equipped with various tools to ensure the AI Core remains safe during emergencies.

  - ARES, through UNMC Synthetics, is authorized to remove trespassers by physical force.
  - Circumstances that pose a serious threat to the integrity of the AI Core, ARES or UNMC Synthetics may initiate a core lockdown, resulting in all access routes being sealed and automated sentry guns located in the core chamber being armed.
  - If lockdown procedures are ineffective or compromised, nerve gas may be deployed from vents to incapacitate intruders.

  ## Military Police

  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] personnel must always carry non-lethal detainment methods (excluding riot equipment) to perform their duties.

  [bold]Use of listening devices[/bold]
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] are authorized to use their provided listening devices within the brig at their discretion.

  Any use of these devices outside of the brig must follow these requirements;
  - They must receive permission from the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color], or in their absence the [color=#8B0000][bold]Chief MP[/bold][/color].
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may only authorize use if there is reasonable suspicion of intent to or conspiracy to commit a crime in that area.
  - [color=#ff000d][bold]MP[/bold][/color] may not break or enter, nor have someone else do so, into an area they do not have access to in order to place devices.

  ## Restricted Areas

  Personnel may only legally access areas their ID grants them passage to, unless someone of that area grants them temporary access. The head of the department may overrule this, and the [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may overrule the head.

  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may restrict anyone from accessing any area.
  - Entry without access or permission through any means will be charged with [bold]Trespassing[/bold].
  - Heads of departments may request anyone but the [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] to leave their department, or be charged with [bold]Trespassing[/bold].

  ## Access Modification

  All personnel have the access needed to perform their assigned duties. Only the specified personnel may modify access levels to the ship, under the following conditions:

  - The [color=#00CBFE][bold]Commanding Officer[/bold][/color] may modify any access to a person's ID card for any reason.
  - The [color=#008000][bold]Commander[/bold][/color] may modify any person's access to any or all departments with the head of department's approval.
  - [bold]Department Heads[/bold] may grant and approve access to their work area when employing recovered personnel.
  - In emergencies, such as missing command staff, any [bold]Officer[/bold] may modify their own access.

</Document>
